web 3.0 has the potential to change the
internet as we know it forever you're
still early in catching the trend right
now and building your first blockchain
application acquire the skills get a
high paying job or create your own web
3.0 projects that can make you money
hello there and welcome to a project
video where you'll build and deploy a
modern real world web 3.0 blockchain
application and let me tell you i
haven't been this excited for a video
for a long time with a stunning design
connected to the blockchain metamask
pairing interaction with smart contracts
sending ethereum through the blockchain
network writing solidity code and much
more crypt is the best web 3.0
blockchain application that you can
currently find on youtube you might be
wondering what are the prerequisites for
building such a fantastic website don't
worry this course is entirely beginner
friendly no web 3.0 blockchain or
solidity knowledge required think of
this as your first real blockchain
application
we're going to start easy and then move
to more complex topics i will explain
every step of the way in this video
you'll learn how to connect a regular
react.js application to the blockchain
and pair it to your ethereum wallet
using metamask you'll also learn how to
write smart contracts on the ethereum
network using the solidity programming
language
essentially in this single video you'll
learn how to create a full-fledged web
3.0 application that allows users to
send transactions through the blockchain
each transaction will then be paired
with a gif and it will be forever stored
on the blockchain
to support this video leave a like
comment and subscribe
it shouldn't take more than a few
seconds and i really appreciate it
if this video reaches 20 000 likes i'm
recording a second web 3.0 video
in the end we'll also deploy the
application so that you can share it
with your friends put it on your
portfolio and get a job you can also
turn this into a real web 3.0
application that other people can use
please allow me to give you a quick demo
of the application that you're going to
build in this video
as you can see we didn't only include
the web 3.0 functionality and leave the
page with no styles you're going to
build a modern fully responsive website
that's going to look like this so once
somebody joins the application they need
to click connect wallet button
this is immediately going to trigger a
meta mask connection and it's going to
ask us which account do we want to
connect in this case that's going to be
account 1 so let's click next
and let's click connect
instantly you'll notice that the address
of our account is right here on this
nice ethereum card
and if we open up metamask you'll be
able to see that our account is now
connected
it might seem like we have five ethereum
in our wallet but don't be fooled we'll
be doing our entire testing on the
robson test network
with that said how do we actually send
ethereum through our application
we can do that by switching our account
to account number two and let's copy the
address of our second account
now we can paste that address right here
we can choose the amount of ethereum we
want to send let's do
0.01 in this case and in here you can
choose the keyword you want to attach to
your specific transaction this keyword
is going to be saved as data in the
blockchain so in this case let's simply
write test
and you can also pass an additional
piece of data which is a message so
let's say hello there from account one
and finally let's click send now
metamask is going to ask us if we want
to send one ethereum so let's go ahead
and click confirm
and then a second notification is going
to appear and this is going to be a
contract interaction so in here we are
actually interacting with our solidity
ethereum smart contract so let's click
confirm as you can see our transaction
is being sent as we speak and our
loading is now gone so let's scroll down
and see if our transaction is here we
also have this nice section that
explains our application and right here
we have our latest transactions as you
can see right here each transaction is
stored in the blockchain forever we can
see the address of the account that sent
that ethereum
and not only that if you click it it's
going to open up an ether scan and
you'll be able to see that this is a
real address that's sending real
transactions through the blockchain
isn't this crazy we can also see who are
we sending the ethereum to and the
amount of ethereum that we are sending
there is also our message and here is
our gif in this case i think we type
test so this is indeed testing and we
can see the correct date and time of our
transaction you can see right there we
have some other transactions that have
been made through our own network
and that's it at the bottom we have a
simple footer and that makes our entire
application the real focus is going to
be to implement web3 into our react
application make it send transactions
through the blockchain and then store
those transactions and show them right
inside of our application we've got a
lot to cover so let's go ahead and get
started
[Music]
before we start building out our project
let's first get the hosting and the
domain name for our new site
hostinger is my personal recommendation
and right now they're offering crazy
deals so i simply needed to show this to
you they offer a great price to quality
ratio high speed servers and most
importantly 24 7 chat support
let's see what's offered with some of
the most popular hosting plans and let's
grab those deals hostingers plans are
incredibly cheap i mean one dollar a
month for hosting for one website and
you also get a free ssl certificate
that means that you'll have https
security in my case i'm gonna go with
the premium shared hosting because it
offers a few great things we'll need
when building out our crypt project it
gives you a free email account free ssl
but most importantly it gives you a free
domain name of course if you still
decide to get single shared hosting you
can later buy the domain name separately
all web 3.0 applications need to be fast
reliable and secure
that's why having a good domain name and
an ssl certificate makes all the
difference
of course improving your load times will
definitely make your page stand out from
the crowd
since i've partnered with hostinger they
decided to give you an even bigger
discount you can find the link and the
discount code in the description enjoy
once you visit the link in the
description let's choose a plan
i've selected premium shared hosting and
here we have to choose the period of our
hosting
with this crazy discount going on right
now i'll definitely choose 48 months to
save the most money and down below you
can choose your payment method and then
you can enter your coupon code that's
going to be javascript mastery all
uppercased
that's going to give you an even bigger
discount on your hosting package after
you purchase it you'll be redirected to
hostinger's dashboard i'll see you there
as you can see i'm personally using
hostinger for my brand for all of my
websites if you've purchased premium
shared hosting then you should have this
claim your free domain button right here
if you bought a single shared hosting
then you can go to domains and then
purchase the domain from here
in my case i'll click the claim domain
button
let's try something like
cryptomastery.com
and let's check availability and that
seems to be free this is actually a
great domain so let's go ahead and claim
it
and our domain name is being set up as
we speak
and there we go the process took about a
minute and it's fully set up what we can
do right now is go back to home
and then we can set up our premium
shared hosting we can click start now
and as you can see hostinger offers
immediate hosting for wordpress and
woocommerce but in this case we can
click this button skip i will start from
scratch
in here we can choose the domain name
for our site if you haven't claimed your
free domain you can do that right here
but if you have you can choose it right
here so i'm going to go with
cryptomastery.com and let's click select
finally we can finish the setup the
setup is being initialized and after
that is done we'll be able to start
coding out our project and then at the
end of the video we'll deploy our
website while our hosting is setting up
i just wanted to quickly let you know
that there is a github repository
containing the entire code for this
project
so if you ever get stuck just make sure
to visit the github link down in the
description and compare your code with
the code that's on here that'll help
solving all of your issues
while you're here i would also
appreciate it if you gave this
repository a star
with that said let's check if our
hosting is fully set up
and there we go our website is ready
let's go to the control panel by
clicking the manage site button
at the end of this video as i've
mentioned we're going to deploy our
project using hostinger's file manager
so with that said i know you've been
waiting for it let's dive straight into
the code
as we always do in javascript mastery we
are going to start from the bare
beginnings and that is creating a new
folder on our desktop
just create an empty folder and call it
however you like in this case i'm going
to call it web 3.0
as soon as you create it feel free to
open an empty visual studio code window
or your code editor of choice and then
simply drag and drop the folder into it
now let's expand our editor and the
setup process is going to be a bit
different from our usual videos we're
going to create one new folder which is
going to be called client
this is where our react application is
going to be
and we're going to create another folder
which is going to be called smart
underscore contract
as the name says this is where our
solidity contract will go
now that we have those two folders we
can initialize our react application
we can go to view and then terminal
we can clear the console and then cd
into client
now our client side is opened instead of
using create react app to initialize our
application in this video we're going to
use vite this is a new technology that i
found and it installs builds and starts
your react applications in a few seconds
we no longer have to wait until create
react app initializes our application so
let's get started
the only thing you have to do to create
your react application is scroll down
and run npm init white at latest
of course if you haven't used npm before
then just make sure to download and
install node then you'll be able to run
all of the npm commands
with that said let's go back to our
terminal and right here we can just type
npm
init
vite add latest if you're running this
command for the first time the terminal
is just going to ask you if you want to
install wide so simply press enter
in my case the project setup began
instantly
for our project name let's simply say
dot slash because we are already in the
folder we want to create our project in
let's choose the package name which is
going to be crept in my case but feel
free to call it however you'd like
let's choose a framework i'm going to go
with react
and a variant is going to be simply
react
and that's going to be it now we can
simply run npm install
this process took just 9 seconds and now
we can run npm run
dev
and in only 500 milliseconds it loaded
and you can control click localhost 3000
and our react app is initialized i'm
still not sure how i haven't heard about
white before
for all of our styles in this project
we're gonna use something called
tailwind tailwind allows us to build
modern websites without leaving our jsx
pages it's a utility css framework which
allows you to shape and style your
designs without having to write a line
of css you just write these utility
classes and that's it
down below in the description i'm going
to leave the link to the installation
with create react app but the process is
the same with vid so let's go ahead and
set up tailwind
the only thing we'll have to do is run
npm install dash d tailwind css post css
and auto prefixer
so let's copy it let's stop the terminal
from running by pressing ctrl c and then
y
and let's simply paste npm install and
install all of the necessary
dependencies
once that is done we can also run mpx
tailwind css in it
so right here paste it
and that created a tailwind css config
file there we go and also a post css
config file
now we can copy our template paths so
let's go ahead and copy this
and paste it to tailwind config right
here
now we have to add the tailwind
directives to our css so let's simply
copy this
and inside of the source
index.css we can delete all of this and
simply paste tailwind base tailwith
components and tailwind utilities
finally we can copy this h1
go to our app.jsx
remove all of the jsx from here because
we won't need that
and simply paste that h1
we can also remove the logo the app.css
and the count right here
and of course we are writing the most
modern code so let's convert this into
an arrow function
there we go
this is our react application
finally to check if this works we can
open up the terminal
you can either press ctrl tilde or go to
view and then terminal
and finally we can run mpm run dev
control click the localhost and there we
go
if the words are bolded and underlined
that means that our react application
and tail when gridded are completely
installed
great that was it for our front-end part
now let's initialize all of the code
that we're going to need for our smart
contract
we can stop this terminal from running
by pressing control c and then y
we can cd dot dot to go back into the
root of our directory and then we can cd
into smart underscore contract
right here we're going to run npm init
dash y
this is going to initialize an empty
package json and that's going to be the
starting point of our smart contract but
of course first we need to be able to
see something to code out the
functionality so we're going to focus on
our react application first primarily
the homepage part that allows us to send
transactions and then once that is done
we can go back and implement the
functionality of our smart contract
with that said let's start creating our
react application
let's start with our react application
by creating a basic file and folder
structure
we can do that by creating a new folder
inside of the source folder
called components
and then inside of there we can start
listing all of our components
the first component is going to be
navbar.jsx
inside of there we can create a basic
functional component by typing const
navbar
is equal to a functional component
there we're going to simply return an h1
that's going to say navbar
and just below we need to say export
default navbar
there we go now we can copy this and
then we're going to paste it into every
single new component
so the second component on our list is
going to be footer.jsx
we can paste it here and now we can hold
the alt key and double click all of the
parts where it says navbar
with that we can simply rename
everything to footer
the third component on our list is going
to be loader.jsx
this is going to be a loading spinner so
again make sure to paste it and then
hold alt and then double click all of
the words and simply rename it to the
name of that component in this case
that's loader
the third component is going to be
called
services.jsx we can simply paste it and
rename everything to services
the fourth component is going to be
transactions.jsx
and you might be wondering what is the
difference between js and jsx
jsx just means that we're gonna write
jsx code meaning the react code inside
of that file it doesn't make any
difference you could have used the js
extension with all these with that said
let's continue i'm going to paste our
component and again rename it to
transactions and the final component on
our list is called
welcome.jsx
that's going to be the first part of our
application so we can simply rename
everything to welcome
now to allow our application to import
all of these components in one line we
can create one final
index.js file inside of the components
folder
this is going to allow us to export all
of the components from a single file so
we can say export
default as loader from dot slash loader
now we can repeat this a few more times
and we can rename this from loader to
navbar and then we need to repeat the
process for every single component so
let's do footer next
then we're going to have the welcome
page
we need to have the transactions
and finally
services
now that we have all of our components
we can go into app.jsx and we can import
them right here
let's type import in curly braces navbar
welcome
footer
services
and
transactions and all that is coming from
dot slash components
now inside of our app instead of having
this h1
we can create a div that's going to have
a class name equal to
min dash h dash screen
this is going to be a div with a
specific width and then inside of there
we can create another div that's going
to have a class name
equal to gradient dash bg dash welcome
and inside of there we can put our nav
bar
and we can also put our welcome
and just below that div we're gonna have
the services
we're gonna have the transactions
and finally we're gonna have our footer
with that said our basic file and folder
structure is now fully set up this
definitely took a few minutes but now
whenever we start implementing another
piece of code we can simply control
click and we can start implementing that
specific component the structure is done
now we are ready to start coding
now before we start implementing the
code i like to have a clean working
environment so we can hold ctrl and then
press w a few times to close all of our
currently open files
the only thing we need right now is
client source
app.jsx we can also open up the terminal
and we can cd into client and run it for
one final time so that's going to be npm
run dev
let's open it up
and as you can see we have navbar
welcome services transactions and footer
now this is just a blank paper with five
different components but soon enough
these are going to be entire sections of
our front-end application
let's start by importing some default
css styles we're going to code out all
of the components together but to give
us a jump start on this video i'm going
to just give you a list of all of the
generic styles and backgrounds and
gradients that way we won't have to
write them by hand
so let's go to index.css
and right here you can paste the file
that you can find in the description
it's going to be under styles and other
code there's going to be a github gist
containing the entire index.css file as
you can see we're not doing any logic
here we're simply importing a specific
font setting up some default styling and
then importing all of the gradients i'm
going to give you a moment to get this
index.css file and then we can dive
right in if you've imported the file
correctly you should notice that there
is a gradient on our navbar and on our
welcome section so now is the time that
we start coding them out let's start
with our navbar so we can go to app.jsx
and then simply control click the navbar
component inside of here we can import a
few icons by saying import
h i
menu
alt for
from react dash icons forward slash hi
and below that we can import ai outline
close
and that's going to be coming from react
dash icons forward slash ai in here
we're also going to import the logo so
we can say import logo from dot slash
dot slash images logo dot png
this logo is something that we don't yet
have we don't have the images folder
so i've also prepared an entire zipped
folder of all of the assets that we're
going to use throughout this project to
get it go down in the description unzip
it and then you can paste the images
folder right here inside of the client
directory just paste it that's going to
give you an animated svg hello.svg and
also a logo.png now if you control click
images right here you can notice it's
going to lead you to the crypt logo
let's go back to our navbar and we can
finally start writing out some jsx our
navigation bar is going to be wrapped
with an html5 semantic nav tag
that nav tag is going to have a class
name equal to w dash full
flex
md colon justify dash center
and if you're not sure what some of
these class names mean just make sure to
check out detailing documentation if you
go to
tailwindcss.com forward slash docs the
link is also going to be in the
description you can search for every
single property just right here in the
search let's search for w dash full
and you can notice that w full simply
means that the div is going to take the
entire percentage of the width and
that's the situation with every single
other property for example flex let's
check it out
this is going to set the display of our
div to flex
so whenever you're not sure what some of
these properties mean just go to the
docs and search for that specific name
this means that on medium devices the
justify is going to be center and
on other devices
justify is going to be between
we can also have the items in the center
and set the padding or p-4
now it would be great if we could see
the changes that we code live in the
browser so let's put our browser and the
editor side by side and there we go i've
opened up the browser side by side with
the editor and we are immediately
greeted with an error
right now we are never actually
importing react icons
and for that matter we're not importing
any single package we can see that if we
go to package.json we only have the
default installed packages so let's go
ahead and install all of the necessary
dependencies that our react application
is going to use
we can open up the terminal
press ctrl c to stop it from running and
then y in here we can type npm install
and let's of course install a package
called react dash icons
and the only other package we're going
to use is called ethers this is going to
allow us to interact with the blockchain
and with our smart contract everything
else we're going to code on our own so
let's press enter and wait until these
two packages are installed and while i
was speaking they were already installed
so we can rerun our application by
running npm run dev
and again make sure that you install
them and run the npm run dev inside of
the client directory
great as you can see now we no longer
have the error but we cannot really see
anything yet in the navigation bar so
let's continue coding it inside of our
nav we're gonna have a div
and this div is going to have a class
name
where on medium devices we can say flex
dash 0.5
in square brackets
then usually it's going to be flex
initial
justify dash center and items dash
center
inside of here we're going to render our
image
so we can create a new image tag where
the source is going to be equal to logo
alternative tag is going to be logo and
we can give it a class name equal to
w-32 and cursor dash pointer and there
we go here is our crypt logo just below
this div we can create a ul and an
ordered list
and we can give it a class name equal to
text white
md
column flex
hidden
list dash none
flex dash row
justify dash between
items dash center and finally flex dash
initial
now of course if you save that nothing's
going to happen because we have to add
some list items we're going to create a
new component right here above this one
that's going to be a simple component
for our nav bar item it's going to be a
functional component and it's going to
accept a few props it's going to be
title and class props like this
and the only thing it's going to do is
it's simply going to return an li a list
item that list item is going to have a
class name
equal to but it's going to be a dynamic
block like this
margin x dash 4 which means margin on
horizontal axis
then we're going to have cursor dash
pointer and finally we can render out
all of the class props that we pass into
it and inside of our li we're going to
simply render the title
that means that now we can call our
navigation bar item right here as a
component and that's the beauty of react
reusing it of course we don't simply
want to have one navbar item so let's
create a new dynamic block
create an array where the first item is
going to be market the second item is
going to be exchange
the third item is going to be tutorials
and for the fourth one let's do
something like wallets and then we can
call a dot map method on it
r.map is instantly going to return
something meaning that we won't have
curly braces here just regular
parentheses
and in our function parameters we're
going to pass the item we're looping
over which is going to be either market
exchange tutorials or wallets and we can
also get the index of our specific loop
so for each iteration we want to show
the navbar item like this as a
self-closing tag
and we're going to provide a key equal
to item plus index to make it really
unique and the title can simply be the
item now if we save that you can notice
that we have market exchange tutorials
and wallets
now let's also say that people can log
in to our application so we can create
one final ally that's simply going to
say login
inside of there let's give it a class
name
equal to bg dash and then in square
brackets with a hash sign
2 9 5
2 e3 i found that color to work really
good that's a basic blue color we can
give it a padding y dash too just to
give it some top and bottom padding we
can also give it padding x-7 there we go
and let's give it margin x-4 let's make
it rounded dash full
and also make cursor dash pointer and
finally on hover let's change the
background to be
2 5 4
6 b
d and let's save it
there we go so now we have that hover
effect of course doesn't look that good
right now because we are zoomed in to
300 percent but if we reset it you can
notice that this is looking like a real
navigation bar great now of course as
you've noticed when we zoom it in this
feels more like a mobile view and this
is not good for mobile devices so let's
implement the navigation bar for mobile
devices below this ul we can create a
div and that div is going to have a
class name equal to flex and relative
we'll also have to have a state that's
going to indicate whether the mobile
navigation bar is currently opened or
not so we can say const toggle menu and
set toggle menu that's going to be equal
to react dot use state and let's simply
pass false at the start it's going to be
closed on mobile devices
now inside of the div we can open a
dynamic block of code and we're going to
check if the toggle menu is currently
turned on we can go into a new line and
say if it is currently turned on meaning
if part of this ternary operation
in that case we can render the ai
outline close icon as a self-closing tag
and else we can render the hi
menu alt4
also as a self-closing tag
now we can hold the alt key and press on
both lines right here and here because
most of the properties are going to be
similar
font size is going to be 28
then we're gonna have a class name equal
to text dash white
md column hidden
cursor
dash pointer
and we also need to provide an on click
where we're going to have a callback
function and
we can set the toggle menu to be equal
to if it is currently open we want to
set it to false or closed and if it's
not we want to open it up so let's save
this and let's also reload our page
open up the inspect element and notice
where our error is it looks like we
haven't imported react in this file and
that error is coming from here where
we're trying to use use state recently
with a new update of react you no longer
have to import react in jsx files but it
looks like that in most cases you'll
definitely need to import either react
or just some specific hooks like in this
case use state from react there we go
let's save it and there we go we have
our navigation bar
and if you click it it changes the state
from the menu to the close icon so now
when our menu is actually toggled on we
need to be able to show it so just below
we can open a new dynamic block and say
if toggle menu and and
meaning that the code inside of this is
going to show only when the toggle menu
is set to true
we can show a ul
inside of there we can render an li and
this ally is going to have a class name
equal to text dash xl w dash full and
margin y dash 2.
inside of there we want to show the ai
outline close icon
that's simply going to have an on click
property
with a callback function
and we simply want to set the toggle
menu to be equal to false like this
there we go this is only if the
navigation bar is opened and then below
that we need to again loop through all
the items so we can simply copy this
where we're mapping our market exchange
tutorials and wallets let's copy it and
paste it just below this li since this
is a mobile navigation bar we're going
to make use of that class props so let's
pass class props is equal to
mi-2 for margin and tax dash lg
let's save it
and there is our mobile navigation bar
now it might be better to simply open up
inspect and go to the mobile view there
we go but now we can see both the
desktop view and the mobile view we
definitely have to fix that and i've
noticed the error that i have in here
instead of hidden i have an extra t at
the end so if i remove it you'll notice
that our desktop navigation bar
disappears the only thing left to do is
to provide the class names for our
mobile navigation so just below right
here we're gonna have a lot of classes
for our ul
so let's start by saying class names or
class name is equal to a string
and it's going to have the z index equal
to 10
it's going to be fixed
the top property is going to be set to 0
and also right property is going to be
set to two
padding is going to be set to three
let's save it and see if that made any
difference okay now you can see that
this is coming on top of our navigation
bar then we're going to have width dash
and then in square brackets
vertical width like this there we go now
it appears almost in the middle let's
also set the entire height so height
screen like this
we can give it a shadow dash 2xl
and on medium devices we can make it
hidden then the list is going to be set
to none because we don't want to have
that list items and let's go into the
new row it's going to be a bit easier to
read and write let's make it flex flex
dash call
justify dash start
items dash and there we go now we're
starting to position it
rounded dash md and we're gonna add a
special class which is going to be our
own gradient
blue dash
glass morphism
that's going to give it that glossy
glass effect
let's make the text dash white and also
animate dash slide dash in
there we go so now this is looking more
like a proper mobile navigation bar and
it looks like it's not touching the
right side so right here where we have
right dash 2 let's put minus in front of
it to move it to the right side this
basically means -2 on the right side now
if you close it that looks great and yes
this is a proper mobile navigation bar
later on once we have the gradients all
over the place for services and
transactions it's going to look even
better because there won't be a white
background behind it but that's going to
be it for our mobile navigation bar
now let's toggle off the device toolbar
and this is how it looks like on desktop
with that said our navigation bar is now
done
and we are ready for the main part of
our show which is the welcome page with
that great ethereum card and the ability
to send transactions
to start creating our welcome page we
can control click into the welcome
component we can start by importing a
few icons
by typing ai
fill
play
circle
and that's going to be coming from react
dash icons forward slash ai
then we can also import si
ethereum
and that's going to be coming from
react dash icons forward slash
si and finally we can import
bs info
circle
and that's coming from
react dash icons
forward slash bs
inside of here we're also going to
import our loader component because
later on something is going to load here
so we can import that
from
dot slash that's it because we are
already in the components folder
now we can start with the jsx part of
our welcome component
we're going to have one div that's going
to wrap everything right here
that div is going to have a class name
equal to flex
w dash full justify dash center and
items dash center
this is centering the entire welcome
part
then we're going to have one more div
that's going to have a class name equal
to flex
md flex dash row
flex dash call
items start
justify dash between
md padding 20
padding y 12 and padding x4
there we go you can see it provided some
paddings
and there is one final div inside of
that div that's going to have a class
name equal to flex
flex dash one
justify dash start
flex dash call and md mr which is margin
right 10 there we go
now inside of there we can create an h1
this h1 is simply going to say something
like send crypto
and then we can have a br tag
and say across the world
if we save it it should be somewhere
around here but it's black so it's not
easily visible there we go so let's
provide some class names
we can say class name is equal to text
dash 3xl that's going to make it a lot
bigger
on smaller devices we can say text dash
5 xl to make it even bigger on small
devices
we can make it text
white
give it a text gradient
and finally padding y dash one
there we go this is already looking so
much better
now below that h1 we can have a padding
that padding is going to say something
like explore the crypto world buy and
sell crypto
currencies easily on crypto this is just
some placeholder text again we have to
add some class names so we can say class
name is equal to text dash left
margin top dash five
text dash white
font dash light on medium devices width
is going to be
9 divided by 12 and on all other devices
it's going to be w dash 11 out of 12
spaces and we can also say the text base
is going to be the size
there we go now we have the left part of
our welcome section now below that b tag
we're going to have a button that button
is going to have a type
equal to button
it's also going to have an on click and
on click we want to connect to the
wallet so we're going to have a connect
wallet function which we can create
right here
const connect wallet is going to be a
basic arrow function again it's not
going to do anything yet but later on
we're going to implement the
functionality
now this button is also going to have a
few class names so we can say class name
is equal to flex it's also going to be
flex dash row justify dash center
items dash center
margin y meaning on top and bottom five
b g dash and then in square brackets
hash two nine five two e three that's
that blue color padding dash three
rounded dash full cursor dash pointer
and then on hover we want to change the
background color bg dash
in square brackets that's going to be
hash 2 5 4
6 b d and of course to be able to see
something we have to write something
inside of that button and that's going
to be connect wallet of course we need
to make our text wide so let's also wrap
our connect wallet in a paragraph like
this
and that paragraph is going to have a
class name equal to text dash white
text dash base and font dash semi bold
there we go looking better already now
below that button we're going to create
a div that's going to serve as a grid
for all of our features so right here we
can say class name is equal to grid on
small devices grid dash calls dash 3
usually grid dash calls dash 2
with dash 4 and margin top is 10.
now we can create a div for each
specific cell so the first div is going
to have the class name equal to
and it's going to be a dynamic block
like this
rounded
dash tl which stands for top left dash
2xl and then we also want to provide a
variable which is going to be
common
styles like this
this common styles is going to be just a
string of common styles but it's going
to be quite long so we're simply going
to type it out by hand at the top and
import it later on so const common
styles is equal to a string and again
just you don't have to write everything
by hand and copy what i do i'm simply
going to paste the styles right here
it's going to have some minimum height
paddings and setting up the flex
containers with the borders the link to
this line is also going to be in a
github gist down below and as soon as
you save it you'll notice that we have
our first cell of our grid inside of
there we can say something like
reliability now below that we can create
one more div that's going to have a
class name equal to
common styles again so we're reusing the
same styles and in here we can say
security now below that we can have one
more div which we can basically
replicate from here that div is going to
say ethereum
and instead of rounded top left it's
going to be rounded top right or tr
there we go
then we can duplicate that below the
bottom one can say web 3.0 like this
this doesn't have to be uppercased and
this is going to be rounded bottom left
like this
then we can duplicate this one where it
says security there we go put it below
and it's simply going to say low fees
and the last one we need we're going to
duplicate the web 3.0 and just change
this to bottom right
now we have our grid of features where
we're mentioning all of the specific
services that we provide
and i've almost missed it the last cell
is going to say blockchain now below
three of these divs so right here we can
create a new div and everything inside
of here is going to be the right side of
our desktop welcome view meaning our
form and that nice card that you saw the
start
this here is what i'm referring to this
is the finished application and now
we're building this card component which
is looking pretty great but that's
mostly just a div with some gradients
and then we're going to implement this
form just below so let's go back and
start implementing that card element
first we have to create a few divs that
are going to separate our left layout
from the right layout so let's say div
with a class name is equal to flex
flex dash call
dash one
items dash center justify dash start
w dash full
then we're gonna have the md
empty
zero meaning on medium devices that
margin top is going to be 0 and then
usually margin top is going to be set to
10.
of course we cannot see any differences
because our div is empty so let's create
the inner div right here
that div is going to have a class name
equal to
padding dash 3
justify dash and
items start
flex dash column or call
rounded xl
height is going to be set to 40 so h40
on small devices the width is going to
be set to 72
usually the width is going to be set to
full
margin y meaning on top and bottom is
going to be five we have that special
class called if
dash card and finally we have that white
dash
glass morphism there we go and these are
the classes coming from our initial
index.css you can notice that in here we
have that gradient welcome gradient
services as well as the white glass
morphism and that ethereum card and
don't worry this wasn't written by hand
there are a lot of online free services
that allow you to create gradients for
you with that said now we have this
great looking ethereum card inside of it
we can create a new div and this div is
going to have a class name
flex justify dash between
flex dash call
w dash full and height dash full
we're basically making it a flex
container now inside of there we can
create a new div that's going to have a
class name
flex justify dash between and items dash
start finally we can have one final div
that's going to be a wrapper for the
icon and that div is going to have a
class name equal to w dash 10
height dash 10
rounded dash full
border dash 2
border dash white
there we go you can immediately notice
it on the right side and it's also going
to be flex
justify dash center and items dash
center
inside of it we're going to put that
ethereum icon
so we can say s i
ethereum
and we can give it a font size
like this equal to 21 and color is going
to be equal to
fff and there we go now we added that
ethereum logo to the card now just below
this div we can also put the bs info
circle which is another icon
it's going to have a font size
equal to 17
and it's also going to have a color
equal to fff there we go now below this
div we're gonna have one more div
this div won't have any class names
but inside of there we can render a
paragraph
that paragraph is going to have a class
name of text
white
font dash light and text sm inside of
there later on we're going to render the
address of the blockchain wallet that's
currently connected to our application
so right here we can now simply say
0x and then put some random letters dot
and then close it again this is how
usual addresses look like
they are written in hexadecimal and
finally we can duplicate this paragraph
below it's going to have text white
font is going to be semi-bold
we can also put the text to be lg and
give it a margin top 1. inside of there
we can simply say ethereum and for now
we can just say address here i think
that looks a bit better there we go
great so now we have the top part of our
form which is this great looking card
now we are ready to actually implement
the form and to do that we have to go a
few divs down so that's going to be 1 2
3 and now right here we're going to
create one more div so this div is going
to be our form this div is going to have
a class name equal to
padding dash 5 or p-5 on small devices
the width is going to be set to 96
w dash full
flex flex dash call
justify dash start
items center
and blue dash glass morphism
there we go you can notice that blue div
right there
but now we have to add some inputs
inside of it
and we're gonna have a lot of similar
inputs so it might simply be easier to
create a new component which is going to
form our input
so right here at the top we can create
an input component which is going to be
a basic arrow function and that input is
instantly going to return some jsx code
so instead of curly braces we can just
use parentheses here
and we can create a basic html input tag
that input is going to have a place
holder
and a placeholder is going to be equal
to placeholder
so you might be wondering where is this
placeholder variable coming from
well we're going to pass it through the
props
so what are going to be some other
things that we're going to pass through
props
well let's try to create a basic version
of our input component
it's going to look like this it's going
to be a self-closing input tag
we're going to give it a placeholder is
equal to
and our first field is going to be the
address 2. so who are we sending the
ethereum to
then it has to have a name equal to
address to in a camel case like this
then it has to have a type which is
going to be equal to text and finally it
has to have a handle change which is
going to be equal to handle change
that handle change is a function that we
haven't yet created so for now i'm
simply going to put a basic callback
function and as you can see we have our
input right here
now we know which props are we passing
so we can get all of them right here
we're gonna get the placeholder
name
type
value and handle change below the
placeholder we can say type is equal to
type we can also set the step of our
number input to be 0.0001
because ethereum values are incredibly
high so even the smallest of amounts
makes a huge difference then we need to
pass in the value equal to value
and then we are also going to pass d on
change which is going to be equal to a
callback function where we are going to
get an event right here and we can call
that handle change that we're passing
through props and pass the name and the
event like so and finally let's give
some class names to this input classname
is equal to and that's going to be a
string of margin y dash 2.
now let's save it right now it looks bad
so let's add a few more classes
w dash full this is going to make it
extend
rounded dash small this is going to make
it rounded a bit
padding dash 2 to apply some padding
outline dash none
bg dash transparent there we go
text white
border dash none
text dash small
white dash glass morphism
and that's going to be it
our input immediately looks so much
better
and you can see how much these utility
classes that tailin provides us make
things easy for us
now we can duplicate this input a few
more times just below that's the only
reason why we created a new custom
component in the first place
so one two three we want to have four of
these inputs our second input is going
to be the amount of ethereum so we can
say amount in ether
and that's going to be amount which is
the name of our input and the type is
going to be set to number
the handle change we can leave empty for
now then the third input is going to be
the keyword in parentheses this is going
to be a gif or gif however we want to
pronounce it and then that's going to be
the keyword name and then our last field
is going to be
enter
message
that's going to be the message we want
to transfer over the blockchain
and the name is going to be the message
type is going to be text
and there we go this is already looking
so much better
below of our inputs we're going to have
one more div but this is going to be a
self-closing div it's going to have a
class name equal to h dash
and then in square brackets 1px like
this
w dash full
bg dash
gray-400 and
margin y dash 2. this is going to be a
line just like this one and right here
just below that we can have the is
loading state so if it is loading
then we want to show something like this
else we want to show something else
we don't have access to this is loading
variable yet so let's simply try setting
this to true
and then we're going to render out our
loader like this
if we save that you're gonna notice that
we also have to type something in here
so for now let's simply put that as a
div
and i think in here with dark flares it
does say a loader later on we're going
to implement that loader component but
now if we are not loading so if it's
false
then we want to show a button
and that button is going to have a type
which is going to be equal to button
that button is also going to have an
onclick property which is going to be
handle
submit
and this is going to be a function that
we need to create just at the top so
right here let's say const handle submit
is a functional component right here
that button is going to say send now
like this and let's give it some class
names
so class name is going to be equal to
text dash white
there we go send now
w dash full
margin top or mt-2
border dash and then in square brackets
1 px
like this
p
border dash and then we have to type a
color so let's do
square brackets hash
3d4 f7c like this
let's make it rounded dash full
and finally every button needs a cursor
dash pointer
there we go
that is our send now button
so now let's also implement this loader
component we can do that by doing a
control click and our loader component
is simply going to be a div a div that's
going to have a class name equal to flex
justify dash center
items dash center and padding dash y3
and finally we're gonna have one inner
self-closing div that's going to have a
class
name equal to animate dash spin also
rounded dash full
h-32 with dash 32
border dash b-2 and border dash red-700
now if we go back to welcome and set
this to true
you're gonna notice that nice red
spinning border of course later on we're
gonna have the is loading state here
that's going to dynamically change as
soon as we click the send now button now
let's expand our browser just a bit to
see how does it look like on desktop
devices there we go now let's check out
the finished version and it looks like
this is panning a bit more to left and
right it's taking a bit more space if
you take a look this is all closed down
to the middle so let's see what do we
have to do to achieve this kind of look
i'm going to collapse this one more time
and to achieve this kind of look we're
going to create a custom media query
so far we've used medium right here but
let's use something like mf which is
going to stand for full
we're going to use that mf right here
we're going to also use that mf right
here
and finally we're going to use it in one
last place which is going to be on line
66 right here right here where we say md
is equal to empty zero that's going to
be mf
and if we zoom this out a bit we should
have two mds left
and we should have three mf's
that way you'll know that everything is
right
so now you might be wondering what is
this mf
if you went to tailwind they're not
going to have a specific medium full or
something like that media query this is
a media query that's going to be
appended to tailwind by us
more specifically you can open up your
file explorer and then go to
tailwind.config.js
inside of here we just have the basic
config but again in the description
there's going to be a link to a github
gist that's going to contain the updated
tailwind.config.js
the only thing that's changing here is
the font as well as we're adding that
specific screen which is medium full and
that's going to provide it a bit more
width
we're going to also add the slide in
animations
so just go into the github just below
copy the tailwind config and paste it
straight into here and as soon as you've
done that we can now expand this and
zoom it in a bit and this is looking
great
i actually preferred having the window
zoomed in so that you guys can see
everything so much better
with that said let's now bring this back
right here
we have our tailbone config and we are
completely done with the layout part of
our welcome component
now we are able to write the address we
want to send the ethereum to write the
amount of ethereum the keyword and the
message so now we are actually going to
connect this to the blockchain and then
we're going to write a solidity smart
contract that keeps track of all of the
transactions that went through the
blockchain
exciting part coming up right now
to start creating the blockchain part of
our application we can close all the
files and folders right here
collapse them and then open up the smart
contract parts of the page
we can also go to view
terminal press ctrl c to stop it from
running
and then we can cd dot to get back into
the root of directory and then cd into
smart underscore contract great
we've already set up the basic package
json but right now it doesn't have any
dependencies
so down in the description you'll be
able to find a list of all the
dependencies that you need to install
instead of typing them out by hand
simply find this command and press enter
this process is going to take about a
minute and as soon as it's done we'll
start creating our smart contract to
create a basic structure for our smart
contract we're going to use hard hat
hard hat is ethereum development
environment for professionals and it
allows you to run solidity locally so
it's going to allow us to test our smart
contract first before deploying it there
we go our packages have been installed
and we are ready to run our first
command which is mpx hard hat
this is going to create a basic project
structure so let's just click enter
create a basic sample project let's
click enter one more time because we
want to create it inside of here
and finally yes we want to add a git
ignore so press enter one more time
you'll notice that we immediately get a
few files and folders for example this
hard hat config file right here as well
as the tests scripts and most
importantly contracts we're going to
explore all of these the first thing we
can do to make sure that everything is
running correctly is run mpx hard hat
test
this command just to run our test script
which then created a basic greeter
solidity contract
of course this was just a test we're
going to create our own contracts right
away before we start writing the
solidity code it's going to be a lot
easier if you go to extensions and then
install the solidity extension this is
simply going to provide you some syntax
highlighting so your code is going to
look better and it's going to be easier
to write it so just make sure to install
it
after you've done that
we can go back into our explorer and we
can delete the greeter.soul contract
that is the demo contract created for us
by hardhat
we can delete it and we can create a new
smart contract called transactions
dot sol as in solidity inside of here we
can start writing the code for our first
ever solidity smart contract
solidity is a fairly new programming
language used for ethereum blockchain
and it's a combination of a few
languages the creators of solidity got
inspired by javascript java c plus plus
rust and many other languages therefore
not only making solidity extremely
versatile but also making it intuitive
as we start to write code in solidity
you're gonna notice that all of that
seems similar maybe from java javascript
but it's definitely going to make sense
as it's almost written in pure english
first we can start by choosing the
version of solidity we want to use
in this case i'm going to write pragma
solidity and then
the carrot sign which is shift and 6 on
my keyboard and then 0.8.0
and we need to write semicolons at the
end you'll also notice that we get a
warning right here saying that we need a
license so right here we can copy this
spdx license identifier unlicensed so
simply make sure to copy it and put that
as the comment above your code that's
going to make that warning go away and
now that we have our license and we've
chosen the version of solidity we want
to use we can immediately create our
contract so you can simply write
contract you can give it a name
in this case the name is going to be the
same as the name of our file which is
going to be transactions this contract
is serving a purpose of a class in
object-oriented programming languages
one difference between solidity and
javascript is that in javascript you can
simply say let and then say for example
test is equal to five
and then later on you can redeclare that
test to be a string of five
in most other regular programming
languages you cannot do that because
they are statically typed meaning you
have to define the type of the variable
at the start
that can either be a string or a number
like integer
so in this case let's define our first
variable by saying you and 256
and we can call it transaction
count
this is going to be a simple number
variable that's going to hold the number
of our transactions
just after that we can create something
known as an event we have to give a name
to this event which is going to be
called transfer
think of this like a function that we're
going to emit or call later on
this function is going to accept a few
parameters
each one of our transactions or
transfers has to have an address
from
and this address here is going to be the
type and the from is going to be a
variable name
then we also need to have the address of
the receiver so that's going to be our
second parameter
then we want to have a number meaning
you and again that is just a type and
the name of the variable is going to be
amount we also need to have a string
equal to message which is just the name
we need to have another you and 256
which is going to be a timestamp so this
is going to be a number that's going to
say when did we send that transfer
and finally we can have one last string
which is going to be the keyword this is
going to form our event which later on
has to be emitted from somewhere now
similar to creating this event we can
also create a struct or a structure
let's call it transfer
struct
and that's going to be similar to an
object but we're not actually declaring
an object here we're just specifying
what properties is this object have and
of what type are they going to be so we
can say it's going to have an address
and the name of that property is going
to be sender this is the type this is
the name of the property it's also going
to have another address which is going
to be a receiver it's also going to have
a u end which is going to be amount it's
going to have a string which is going to
be message
uint 256 is going to be timestamp and
finally a string that's going to be a
keyword
now we know what properties does our
transfer or transaction needs to have we
can also define an array of different
transactions because we want to store
all of them to define our array we can
call it transactions like this but we
have to define of what type are these
transactions going to be so we can say
transfer
struct
and then an array sign this means that
our transactions variable is going to be
an array of transfer structures
meaning an array of objects
hopefully so far everything here makes
sense now we're going to create
different functions we're going to have
one function which is going to be called
add to blockchain again this is just a
name that we personally chose
it's going to look like this just like a
regular javascript function but we
immediately get a warning saying no
visibility is specified did you intend
to add public since this is a class you
have to define the visibility of this
specific function so we're going to say
that this function is public meaning
everybody can access this function now
we can copy this to create two other
functions that we're going to use
the second function is going to be
called get
all transactions this is also going to
be a public function
but it's going to be public
view
returns and now we need to specify what
is this function going to return
and it's going to return
transfer struct
meaning an array
of different structures
and it's going to get it from memory of
course later on in here we're going to
return
transactions
like this
and our last function is going to be
called get
transaction
count
and it's also going to be public and
it's also going to say view
returns
in this case we simply want to return a
number and the number we're going to
return is going to be return
transaction
count remember that's the variable we
created at the start now i know that
this public view returns and then
transfers struct and then returns a
number
we don't have that in javascript and
that might be a blessing and a curse
statically typed programming languages
are great because they set some rules
in that way they are defending you from
yourself to create some mistakes or
errors or bugs in your code now you know
that this function needs to return the
transaction count which is a number that
getall transactions needs to return a
transfer struct array which is just an
array of objects and so on
you also know that the add to blockchain
doesn't return anything it's just doing
some actions so add to blockchain is
going to be the main part of our smart
contract so what are we going to do in
here well first we're going to increment
the transaction count so we can say
transaction count plus equal to one
there is one more transaction right now
than there was before and in here the
linter immediately says undeclared
identifier
looks like i called it counter at the
start but i meant to use just count so
i'm gonna rename it and we no longer
have an error okay so now we just have a
number one transaction two three four
and so on but we haven't actually pushed
our transaction into our array of
transactions
so whenever we call the add to
blockchain from our react application
we're going to pass specific parameters
into it
more specifically we're going to pass
the address
payable
receiver the first parameter we're going
to pass is going to be the receiver and
that's going to be a payable address
then the second thing we can pass is
going to be the u end which is a number
which is going to be called amount we
can also pass a string
memory
message and this memory here it just
means that this is some specific data
stored in the memory of that transaction
whereas receiver is something that must
be there because it's an address amount
also must be there but this message is
just some additional data that we're
passing through that blockchain and
finally we're gonna have one more string
memory field and that's going to be our
keyword now we have access to all of
these variables and we can do something
with them more specifically we can call
our transactions array and call a dot
push method on it
yes solidity also has a dot push method
and it behaves almost in the same way as
it does in javascript we're going to say
what do we want to push and that is our
transfer struct as you can see right
here and the last thing we have to do is
pass in all the parameters that our
transfer struct needs
let's start with the first one which is
the sender and we actually have that
already in the object called message
message.sender
this is something that you immediately
get whenever you call a specific
function in the blockchain it's already
going to be stored there the second
thing we're gonna get is going to be a
receiver and the receiver is just coming
through our parameters
then we're going to have the amount
which is also coming through params then
we're going to have a message we're
going to have the timestamp which is
going to be equal to block.timestamp
so that's going to be the timestamp of
the specific block that was being
executed on the blockchain
and finally we're gonna have a keyword
this is it we're pushing a specific
transaction into the transactions array
this here is not actually transferring
the amount or doing anything because we
haven't yet emitted the transfer event
right now we're just adding this
transaction to the list of all
transactions but we are not actually
making the transfer to do that we have
to emit this event so to do that we can
say emit
transfer
and then we can pass all the same things
that we're passing right here
let's copy them
paste them here
first we have message.sender then we
have a receiver amount message
block.timestamp and the keyword and
don't forget to add a semicolon
finally now that we know that our
transaction count is actually being
updated we can uncomment this line
so now we can actually send back the
transaction count
and we also know that our transactions
are being added to the list of the
transactions
make sure that you have semicolons at
the end of every single line and this is
going to be it
this is our ethereum solidity smart
contract
it's used to transfer the amount and
also to store all the transactions that
come through it great now there's gonna
be a bit of a setup when it comes to
deploying and testing this smart
contract so writing it is not the only
thing you have to do but no worries i'm
going to show you how to do everything
right now to deploy our smart contract
we can go to file explorer and then
scripts
inside of the scripts you'll be able to
find a
samplescript.js
we can rename that script to
deploy.js and we can delete most of the
things from here let's delete all the
comments and require at the top
let's also remake this function as an
es6 arrow function by saying const main
is equal to
async
arrow function like this
there we go
we also don't need these comments
we don't need those comments and let's
also turn the main into an async await
function that's going to look a bit
better so let's call const
run main
is going to be equal to
async arrow function
if you haven't worked with async await
before don't worry it's just a different
way of writing
and dot catch methods basically dealing
with asynchronous code
inside of here we can create a new try
and catch block let's invent it properly
and inside of here we can simply call a
weight and then call the main function
this is going to execute and deploy our
contract once we await the main function
we also have to call the process dot
exit with a zero which means that the
process went successfully okay let's
indent that and if we go into the catch
we can say console.error
and we're gonna pass in the error
and simply process dot exit with a 1
which means that there was an error
and we also have to run this function
run main at the start so we're going to
execute the deploy.js file first this
line is going to be executed which is
going to call the run main function and
then that's going to call our main
function which is responsible for
deploying the contract
so what do we need to change here well
before the solidity contract was called
greeter but now it's called transactions
so we can rename this with transactions
with a capital t
that's going to be equal to await hre
dot ethers dot get contract factory and
then transactions this is like a
function factory or a class that's going
to generate instances of that specific
contract so just below we're going to
have one specific instance of our
contract which is going to be called
transactions with a lowercase t
and that's going to be equal to a weight
transactions with a capital t dot deploy
and we don't have to pass anything as
the first parameter we're going to await
transactions dot deployed and then we're
going to say transactions with a capital
t
deployed to
and that's going to be transactions
dot address with a lower case d so when
we run this script our transactions are
going to be deployed and then we're
going to get the address of our smart
contract deployed on the blockchain
network
but for our contract to be deployed we
need to have some ethereum on our own
wallet already because everything that
you do on the ethereum network requires
something known as gas
which is small fractions of ethereum
used to make something happen
so how are we going to get our test
ethereum to fund the gas for the
deployment of our contract
we can go back to our browser and more
specifically to the robston testnet
faucet the link is going to be down in
the description on test networks faucets
simply provide you with some test
ethereums free of charge the only thing
you have to do is enter your wallet
address and the ethereum is going to be
transferred to your account
some of these faucets run out of
ethereum from time to time so there are
a lot of them available on the internet
and since we are using the robsten
ethereum test network you can simply
google for robs then faucet and then
simply open a few of them up if one of
these faucets doesn't work you can try
the next one and so on you can see we
have this one
this one seems to be down for whatever
reason
this one sends you one ethereum and this
is the one that i found to work the best
keep in mind that retrieving ethereum
through the faucet is not an
instantaneous process
it can take anywhere from around 30
seconds all the way to a few hours
but again i found this specific test
network to work the best hopefully this
is going to allow you to get your
ethereum in no time but to be completely
sure to receive some ethereum definitely
google robsten faucet and then go ahead
and enter your address in few of these
the link is going to be down in the
description
of course in here we have to enter our
own ethereum wallet address so to get it
we'll have to set up our metamask
account let's do that right away
to set up metamask you can go to your
chrome web store or the extension store
of the any other browser that you use
just make sure to search for metamask
although i already have it here and
metamask is simply an extension for
accessing ethereum enabled distributed
applications so this is going to allow
us to inject ethereum web 3.0 api into
every website's javascript contacts
essentially it's going to let us
interact with the blockchain and smart
contracts
so let's go ahead and add it to chrome
and add extension it's going to appear
at the top and we can also pin it once
you click it you're gonna see this nice
fox and it's going to follow your cursor
around and welcome you to metamask let's
click get started if you're first
installing metamask you most likely
don't already have an account so let's
click create a wallet let's click i
agree and you have to choose your
password in this case i'm going to use a
demo password
and let's click create now when working
with cryptocurrencies your password is
not the main thing guarding your account
your secret recovery phase is you're
going to be given a phrase of 12 words
that are the master key to your wallet
and your funds
so if this is your first time working
with cryptocurrencies or wallets make
sure to watch this video first you can
pause my video right here and then we
can click next i'm going to pause it and
click next right away
and in here you can click to reveal your
secret words
this has to be secret and you have to
save these words somewhere to be able to
access your account if you uninstall
metamask
so i'm not going to reveal them here
what you can do is open up notepad on
your pc and then simply copy and paste
them there
then you'll have to click next and in
the next step you'll have to type them
out one by one okay i copied my words
and you simply need to click them in the
order that they were first shown to you
i'm going to do that myself here without
revealing the secret recovery phase and
then we can click confirm
after you've entered your words
correctly you're gonna see a
congratulations screen with the tips on
storing it safely let's click all done
there we go we can close this and this
is our first ethereum wallet
what you can do right now is go to the
top right
and we want to show and hide test
networks once you click that it's going
to lead you to the settings and you want
to toggle this on
now we can scroll up and we can change
from ethereum network to robsten test
network
there we go
now all ethereum shown on our wallets is
going to be robsten test ethereum not
real ethereum
what you can do right now is click on
this fox on the top right
and simply click here to copy your
account address
once you do that we can go back to the
robston test faucet and paste it right
here and say give me robsten ethereum
there we go it sent
0.15 ethereum to our test wallet let's
click metamask again and let's see if it
maybe arrives in about 30 seconds for me
the process took about a minute but
again it's going to depend from time to
time depending on how many people are
currently mining ethereum on the robsten
test network if this doesn't work for
you make sure to test out all of the
other faucets available online and also
give it some time maybe an hour or two
and then we'll be able to continue with
the video
but it's crucial that you have some
ethereum available here it doesn't have
to be a lot just 0.000 something is
going to be enough but we needed to pay
the gas to deploy our smart contract
with that said we are now ready for the
next step of our video and that next
step is to go to alchemy.com
alchemy is going to help us with the
blockchain development meaning it's
going to help us deploy our blockchain
smart contract
what you can do is click get started for
free
once you do that you're gonna have to
enter your credentials and create your
account but as you can see in my case it
immediately logged me in so after you
create your account you should see a
dashboard page that looks like this
as you can see i've already been testing
with a lot of different ethereum wallets
and different networks but i decided
that robsten is the best one to test
with
so now you can click the create app
button on the top right and let's give
it a name something like crypt
of course feel free to use your own name
in the description we can say blockchain
smart
contract
the environment is going to be
development
the chain is going to be ethereum and
the network is going to be robsten
it's incredibly important that you
choose the robsten test network for this
to work of course later on you can
deploy the same contract on the main
ethereum network but for now we're gonna
stay on the test network so that we
don't have to pay real ethereum gas fees
let's click create app
let's click view details for our newly
created application
and now you can click view key in here
you're going to get an http key which
you need to copy now we can go back to
our application
more specifically we can go to
hardhat.config.js
we can delete this entire file and for
now simply paste this here as a comment
so that you don't lose it to start
creating our hard hat config
let's first require
that's going to be a string
add
nomiclabs forward slash hard hat and
then that's going to be waffle
if we google what hard hat waffle is you
can see that it is a plugin to build
smart contract tests so that's exactly
what we're going to use it for
going back to our application we can
create a module dot exports file and in
here we're going to export our hard hat
config
we first need to specify the version of
solidity that we're going to use which
is going to be 0.8.0
then we can specify the networks we want
to work on
that's going to be an object of networks
and we can call it robsten
our robsten needs to have a url and this
is the url that we got from alchemy so
right here we can copy this comment and
paste it here as a string then we need
just one more thing which is going to be
accounts
right here we need to type accounts
which is going to be equal to an array
and we need to pass the address of the
account that we're going to use to fund
this contract
more specifically it's not going to be
an address
it's going to be metamask and then right
here you need to click these three dots
account details and then export private
key
that's what we need
once you click that you'll need to enter
your password
click confirm and then you're gonna get
a private key that you can copy and
simply paste straight into here
great now we have our config file
we have our solidity smart contract and
we have a script that we're gonna use to
deploy that contract
everything seems to be ready
so what do we need to do to deploy it
let's open up the view and then terminal
let's clear it
and let's run the command mpx
hard hat
run
scripts forward slash deploy dot js
dash dash network
robston
and let's press enter
as you can see our contract compiled
successfully and now we are waiting for
the terminal to give us the address of
the deployed contract
and there we go transactions deployed
too and now make sure to copy this we're
going to use this back in the client
side of our application
so let's go to the client side
go to the source and let's create a new
folder called utils or utility functions
inside of here we can create a new file
called constants.js
inside of here we can say export
const contract
address
and that's going to be equal to
to that address you just copied from the
terminal right here but that address was
not the only thing that was generated
once we run the deploy command
the other thing that was generated was
in the smart contract
artifacts
contracts
transactions that sold
and then right here transactions
transactions.json
this is called an abi
and an abi is the contract application
binary interface that's the standard way
to interact with contracts in the
ethereum ecosystem both from outside of
the blockchain and for contract to
contract interactions this contains all
the information about our specific smart
contract
so we need to copy this entire
transactions.json
and we need to paste it into utils more
specifically create a new file called
transactions.json
and just paste it right here
and then back in constants we can import
that api
import api from
dot slash
transactions.json
and just alongside exporting our
contract address we also need to export
const contract avi which is going to be
equal to abi
dot abi
now we have everything we need inside of
our react application to interact with
our ethereum smart contract
and let's also check if we wasted some
ethereum gas fees for the contract
deployment process
if we go back to our application you can
notice that now we have 0.1482
which means that 0 0 28 ethereum was
wasted or spent on gas fees
but let's not worry about that at all
that's great because now we actually
have a smart contract that's going to
save and store all of our transactions
in the blockchain
now that we've built the react welcome
part of our site and deployed an entire
ethereum smart contract
now we are ready to connect the smart
contract to our react application and
actually make it send ethereum through
the blockchain network let's go ahead
and do that right away
we're going to start by cding back into
our react application with cd dot and
then cb client and then we can also run
npm run dev to have our application up
on localhost 3000
now that that is done we can close all
of our files and folders just so we have
a clean working environment
and we can go to client
source and then we can right click the
source and create a new folder
that folder is going to be called
context
we're going to use react context api
around our entire application that's
going to only serve the purpose of
connecting to the blockchain that's
going to allow us not to write our logic
all across all of our components we're
only going to write it in one
centralized place and that's going to be
transaction
context dot jsx
inside of here we can import
react
as well as use effect
and also use state
and these are of course coming from
react
then we're going to import in curly
braces ethers
and that's going to be coming from
eaters package
then we need to import the contract abi
as well as the contract address
and these are the things that we created
just now
in dot dot slash
utils forward slash
constants
we also need to create our react context
and we can do that by saying export
const
transaction context is equal to react
dot create context
great
also since we're using metamask we're
getting access to the ethereum object
which we can get by typing const in
curly braces ethereum
and that's going to be equal to window
we are basically destructuring the
ethereum object from
window.ethereum and that is one really
interesting thing if we go back to our
browser go to inspect
and then open up the console right here
and go to info we can try typing window
dot ethereum
and would you look at that there is an
entire object that's going to allow us
to handle our ethereum and blockchain
relation and all of this is here only
due to the fact that we installed and
set up metamask
okay now we know that we have our
contract api contract address ethereum
window object and we are ready to access
the blockchain we are first going to
create a special function that's going
to fetch our ethereum contract and we
can do that by saying const get
ethereum contract
and that's going to be equal to an arrow
function
inside of there we can type const
provider
is equal to new
ethers
and that is the package we installed
previously
dot providers
dot
web 3 provider and then we call that as
a function and pass in
ethereum window object
now that we have our provider we can
also get the signer const signer is
equal to provider dot
get signer and we don't have to pass any
parameters
of course let's go ahead and console.log
all of these things
right here inside of an object
provider
as well as signer and we're going to
also have the third thing which is going
to be const transaction
contract
is equal to new ethers
dot contract
and then we pass in the contract address
we pass in the contract abi right here
and we pass in the signer these are the
three ingredients that we need to fetch
our contract the contract address
remember
we have it here from when we deploy the
project
then the contract api which is this json
file and then finally the signer which
we're console logging right now so
you'll see what that is
and we can also console log the
transaction contract so once we actually
call this function we're gonna get this
kansa log
but right now we have to create our
context because where are we going to
call this we have to have a specific
place where it's going to serve a
purpose for that reason we can create a
new export const
transaction
provider
and that's going to be a react arrow
function and every context provider
needs to get one thing from the props
and that thing is children
every context provider also needs to
return something and this return
statement is in most cases just the
context so transaction context right
here and then dot provider
that way we're wrapping our entire react
application with all of the data that's
going to get passed into it
and inside of here we have to render the
children that means that whatever we
wrap inside of this transaction provider
is going to be rented and it's going to
have access to this value object
let me show you what i mean we're going
to take this transaction provider
go into domain
and right here we can import it let's do
so by saying import
transaction
provider
and that's going to be coming from dot
slash context
forward slash transaction context
the only thing we have to do
is wrap our application
with a so-called transaction provider
there we go
put this here
and that's it
now our entire application is going to
have access to the data that we pass
into it
and by data i mean whatever we put in
here if i say value is equal to test
let's see if we can get this value of
test somewhere else in our code for
example in the components and then
welcome
to get our data we need to go to the top
of the component and then import
that's going to be
transaction context
coming from
dot dot slash
context forward slash transaction
context
and also we have to import
react and with react we have to import
the use context hook
and this is of course coming from react
now inside of our component just at the
top we can simply say const
destructure the value
and that's going to be equal to
use context and then we call it as a
hook and of course we need to provide
the name of the context we want to
access in this case that's the
transaction context
finally let's try to console.log the
value
if that works that means that we are
transferring all the data from this file
successfully to any of all of our
components
back in our application we can see that
we got test from the line 25 of our
welcome jsx file that means that the
data has been successfully transferred
of course we don't want to simply
transfer a value of test we want to
transfer some data that's going to help
us connect to the blockchain
more specifically we're going to have a
new function inside of here that's going
to be called
const check
if
wallet is
connected
so check if wallet is connected is an
async function like this
and inside of there we can check if
there is no ethereum object in that case
we can return the alert that's gonna say
please install metamask
because we cannot do any of this if the
user hasn't installed metamask
then we need to get our metamask
connected accounts and we can do that by
saying const accounts is equal to a
weight
ethereum dot request
and we need to specify an object that's
going to include the method and then in
here we can say what do we want to
request and that's going to be eth
underscore accounts now we can
console.log that to see if we are indeed
getting something
and of course we also need a use effect
because we need to call this function so
i'm going to create a use effect right
here
and we're going to call check if wallet
is connected right inside of there
and it's going to happen only at the
start only at the load of our
application
let's see if we indeed do get our
accounts i reloaded the page and we can
see just an empty array meaning there
are no accounts
so it might be a good idea to create a
functionality for our connect wallet
button
that way we'll be able to click this
button and connect our localhost
application to metamask
the function for connecting our wallet
is also going to be in our context so
right here we can create a new function
const connect
wallet is equal to
async arrow function
and we can create a try and catch block
because we need to be sure that this
succeeds
inside of the try we again need to check
if they have metamask installed so we're
going to add this here
then we have to request a metamask
account which is going to be really
similar to this line so we can copy it
right here
but this time we're not going to check
for ethereum accounts we're going to
check for ethereum
request accounts
request accounts with a capital a right
here that way we're gonna get all the
accounts and then the user will be able
to choose to connect one
or in this case
we can set the current account to be
equal to
accounts and then zero that's going to
connect that first account
set current account is going to be a set
state and you can see that because it's
starting with set but we haven't yet
created it so at the top of our
transaction provider we can create a new
use state field
and that use state field is going to be
called
connected
account and also set connected account
and at the start that's going to be
equal to an empty string
great we also have to provide some error
handling so we can console.log the error
and we can also throw new error
that's going to say
no
ethereum
object like that
and of course we need to pass this
function
right here connect wallet is equal to
connect wallet of course if both the key
and the value is the same in that case
we only need to provide the key and now
we're passing this over to all of our
components
with all of the components of course
that's also going to be coming to our
welcome so right here we can get the
connect wallet
or did we say account let me check
that's going to be connect to wallet
right here and we can now call that
function right here
looks like we won't need this function
right here because we have one in the
transaction context and we're calling it
on the button
now let's save it and see if something
happens once we click that button
i'm going to reload the page and press
connect wallet
and there we go there is a meta mask
notification asking us if we want to
connect this wallet with metamask and we
can choose the account one and click
next
finally let's click connect
it's at connecting and now if we reload
the page
there we go
in our transaction context we have our
connected account that's great
right here inside of the check if wallet
is connected
we can check if there is an account by
saying if
accounts
dot length and then if there is one we
can simply set the current account to be
equal to accounts and then zero
that way at the start of every single
render we're going to have access to our
account and then later on in here we
also want to get all of the transactions
so we're going to have a function call
to get all transactions
but of course we cannot do that yet
because we don't have the part of our
page where we can list them out and we
also haven't sent a single one yet so we
cannot really check that out and then
we're gonna have an else part
and in here we can simply cons a log
no
accounts found
great of course it would also be a good
idea to wrap all of this in a try and
catch block so let's do that try and
catch
the entire code that we have so far is
going to go inside of the try
and then if we are inside of the catch
that means that there is no ethereum
object so we can basically copy what we
have here and paste it here
great
so now at the start of our application
we're calling if check if wallet is
connected right here
and we're setting that current account
looks like i chose a wrong name right
here i said connected account but this
here was supposed to be current
account
and that's going to be
set
current account there we go now we are
setting it and we can also pass it
through context right here
current account
now back in our welcome we can also get
access to the current account variable
and right here where we have our button
we can say if there is a current account
or rather if there isn't a current
account
then we want to render this button
but if there is a current account in
that case there is no need for us to
render this button so now if our account
is connected then we shouldn't be able
to see this button and that's exactly
the case we can no longer see the button
which means that our account is
connected
now we have a function for checking if a
wallet is connected at the start and
also a function for connecting the
account
so now might be a good idea to create
that one most important function which
is going to be called const
send transaction
that's going to be an async arrow
function and this is going to be where
our entire logic for sending and storing
transactions is going to be
we can again create a try and catch
block
inside of the catch we're going to have
this
simplicons logging the error and saying
there is no ethereum object
inside of the try we of course have to
first check if the person has metamask
installed
and then below this we have to get the
data from the form so
in some way we have to get the data from
these item fields right here
all the way to our transaction context
how are we going to do that
think about that for a second
where are we going to create those
states how are we going to pass that
data
the answer is we're going to create
those states right here inside of our
context so right here we can say cons
form data as well as the set form
data
and that is equal to use state
and that's going to be an object that's
going to have the address
to property which is going to be set to
an empty string
it's also going to have an amount which
is going to be a string it's going to
have a keyword which is going to be an
empty string and a message which is
again an empty string
so now that we have that form data we
also need to create a handle change so
we can say const handle
change
is equal to
a function
all handle change functions that
interact with inputs except the event
the keyboard event the key press as the
event and also we're going to pass in a
name
this handle change is dynamically going
to update the form data by saying set
form data is equal to now whenever
you're updating the new state using the
old state you have to provide a callback
function in the state where as the first
parameter react gives you prev state
and we're going to instantly return an
object and you can do that by first
using parentheses and then writing an
object and that object is going to have
the previous state
spread like this
and we can update dynamically name to
include the e dot target dot value this
here is nothing block chain related but
it's definitely a hard to understand
function
this requires some a bit more advanced
react knowledge so if this doesn't make
a lot of sense try setting up your own
small react application where you're
just going to have the form with a few
inputs and then see how the data changes
or how the state changes once you type
into those inputs with this handle
change function there isn't really an
easy way to understand this
rather than trying everything yourself
on a real project with that said we have
our form data set form data and also the
handle change function so let's go ahead
and pass those to our context object so
right here we can pass the
form
data
as well as the set form data and also
the handle change
now back in our welcome we can accept
all of these from the context that's
going to be form
data
set
form data as well as the handle change
so now if we scroll down right here
instead of having an empty callback
function in the handle change we can
delete that again i held alt and then
double clicked and in here we can simply
use the handle change function that's
going to update these inputs dynamically
depending on the name of that specific
input so it's really important that the
names exactly match
what you have in the state
right here with that said let's see
where do we have to use our set form
data or anything else
we have our handle submit here so if we
click it we have to implement that
handle submit function
and right here we can destructure all of
the properties from the form data
by saying const in curly braces address
amount keyword and message
is equal to
form data we simply destructured these
properties then below we can call e dot
prevent default
usually when you submit a form the page
reloads but in react applications we
want to prevent that from happening and
that's why we're calling this function
then we have to check if the user has
filled in the fields so we can say if
no address to
or if there is no amount or if there is
no keyword or if there is no message in
that case we simply want to leave this
function and not submit anything so
we're going to simply return nothing
else if the user successfully filled in
all the fields we can call the send
transaction function like this
we've created that send transaction
function which is right here
but we haven't passed it through props
so we can do that right away right here
send transaction and we can get it right
here instead of set form data because
we're not using that so make sure to get
the sent transaction right here so that
we can call it at the end
now we've created that circle we've
created the state variables here
passed them through the context value
right here
into the welcome the welcome is dealing
with some data and then it's calling the
send transaction button
which is then triggering
this function where we're gonna get the
data from the form i know this might be
a bit hard if you don't have a lot of
experience with react but keep
practicing with state inputs and context
and i'm sure you're gonna get the hang
of it so now we can destructure the
values the same way we did in the
welcome we can even copy that line right
here and paste it here
now we have access to the form data
variables we also need to get our
ethereum contract and remember that is
the function we created right here and
we haven't called it before
so what we can do is we can call it
right inside of the send transaction
that's going to be
get ethereum contract
at the start it's not going to do
anything besides simply cons logging the
values so let's see what is it going to
cause a log
looks like we have a typo so let me
quickly go here and check where that
typo is coming from i'm missing a curly
brace right here but after i added
that's looking good and now we of course
have to click our send now button so let
me type test here
let's send
0.0001 by the way you can use these
arrows here
for the
key award looks like i have a typo there
we can type test and we can type test
right here and click send when we do
that obviously we've got an error saying
e is not defined to fix that we can go
to our welcome and simply get the event
from the parameters i simply forgot
about that but now that shouldn't be an
issue anymore going back we can now
clear the console by pressing this icon
right here and we can click send now one
more time and there we go
we got an object with the provider
i'm going to make this a bit bigger for
you provider is going to be web3
provider with a lot of different
properties that we can choose from
then we have the signer as well
and finally we have the transaction
contract which is the most important
part right here and take a look this
transaction contract is not just any
contract this is our transaction contact
containing the function add to
blockchain
get all transactions as well as the get
transaction count if you remember
correctly these are the exact functions
that we have created inside of our
solidity contract that means that now we
can go to our transaction contract and
instead of cons logging all of these
values we can simply return the
transaction contract now we can go back
to our send transaction and instead of
simply calling it we can say const
transaction contract is equal to
get ethereum transaction contract
now we'll be able to use this variable
to call all of our contract related
functions
great we're doing a lot of stuff now and
i hope it's all coming into place with
just a few more lines we'll be able to
send our first transaction through the
blockchain
now that we have all the data we need
let's send some ethereum
we can say await
ethereum
dot request
and it's going to accept an object with
all of the options
the first option is going to be a method
which is going to be if underscore send
transaction
like this
and then we have to pass some params
params is going to be an array with an
object inside of it
and it's going to have a from property
and this is going to be the current
account remember that's what we stored
straight inside of our state then it's
also going to accept a to address and
where can we find that well look we're
accessing it from the form data so right
here we can say address 2. then this is
going to be a weird one but we have to
choose the amount of gas we want our
transaction to take or spend and all of
the values that you use in the ethereum
network are written in hexadecimal or
hex so we're going to do something like
0x5208
and this has to be in a string now if
you cannot immediately transfer this to
decimal let's take this value and google
something like hex to decimal go to the
first link and paste it here and click
convert
this is going to take 21 000 but it's
not going to be 21 000 ether it's going
to be 21 000 way and that's a sub unit
of ether so if we type 21 000 here
you're going to notice that that is
actually
0.000021 ethereum
so we have to write everything in
hexadecimal values that are then
converted to whey
and then that's behind the scenes
actually just ether but way is a subunit
of ether like a cent is to american
dollar so now we know that this is 21
way and we also have to choose the value
we want to pass so the value is going to
be
the amount right the amount we are
sending right from the form data but
that's not the case if you think about
it the amount is going to be something
like 0.001
or whatever we choose on our form
but this here is a decimal number
so we have to find a way to convert this
into grey or hexadecimal and we can do
that by saying const
parsed amount
is equal to
ethers dot utils dot parse
ether and then in there we can pass in
the amount the ethers package provides
us with utility functions that we can
call and one of those utility functions
is called parse ether which just parses
the decimal amount into
grey hexadecimal amount
so instead of passing the amount we're
going to pass in the parsed amount but
we also have to do dot underscore hex
like this
and that's going to be it for our
ethereum transaction
but this is only sending ethereum from
one address to another we also have to
provide the part where we call the add
to blockchain function so that we store
the transaction that just happened
so let's do that right below this
to store our transaction we can call the
transaction contract
dot add to blockchain as i've mentioned
that's our own function that we've
created on this transaction contract
great so what does our add to blockchain
function need
it needs an address the amount the
message and the keyword so let's take
these values
and put them into here
the address is going to be address 2
then
we want to pass the parsed amount
we want to pass the message and finally
we want to pass the keyword
and we can get a transaction hash which
is a specific
transaction id
so we can say transaction hash is equal
to
a weight
transaction contract
this is an asynchronous action and it
definitely takes some time for the
transaction to go through so we need to
add a loading state
right here at the top we can create a
new use state field which is going to be
called is loading
and then at the start it's going to be
set to false
then we can scroll down and right here
below our transaction hash we can say
set is loading and we're going to set it
to true
below our set is loading we can cons a
log and say in a template string loading
and then dynamically transaction hash
and then
dot hash finally we can call the await
transaction hash
dot wait this is going to wait for the
transaction to be finished
of course with 1a here i had a typo
now after that is done we can call these
two lines again
but we're gonna set the loading to be
false and we're gonna say
success after that is done we can also
get the const transaction and that's
going to be transaction count
which is going to be equal to a weight
transaction contract dot get
transaction count
and once we get the transaction count we
can store it in the state so at the top
we can create one new state
use state
and that's going to be transaction
count
and set transaction count at the start
is going to be equal to zero but in this
case the zero might not be the best way
to set up our transaction account
because it's going to get a reset every
time that we reload our browser
but we're going to store our transaction
count into local storage so right here
we can say local storage
dot get item
and then that's going to be transaction
count
later on we're going to store it there
so we can always keep track of the
current transaction count
now we have this set transaction count
and just below we can call set
transaction count and we can pass in our
transaction count then dot to number
like this
great
and believe it or not that's going to be
it for our send transaction
if we've coded everything out correctly
we should be able to send ether through
the ethereum network
back inside of our browser we can open
up metamask and we can create a new
account because we need to have a
different address that we're going to
send the money to
so let's click account here and let's
click create account we can call it
account 2 or whatever you prefer and
let's click create
now we are on the account 2 and let's
copy the address to clipboard
we can paste it here under address 2.
let's send 0.0005
the keyword can be something like test
and the message can also be test let's
open up our inspect element
go to console
and let's click send
first metamask notification appeared
sending it 0.0005
that is correct and we're going to pay a
bit extra for the fees but that's
completely okay let's click confirm
and then the second metamask
notification is going to appear and it's
going to say contract interaction so
we're going to pay a bit in fees and
this is going to store our transaction
on the blockchain let's click confirm
there we go our hash is loading and this
process usually takes about half a
minute but again it depends on a lot of
factors so it might take a bit longer
for you and there we go i've gotten
success right here now let's close this
and let's open up our metamask
on our account 2 we now have
0.005 ethereum isn't that crazy
and if we go back to our count 1 we're
definitely missing
0.0005 here so
are you sharing the enthusiasm with me
even before creating this video
blockchain related technologies and
cryptocurrencies were incredibly
interesting to me
we just send ethereum through the
blockchain from one address to another
the second address could be anywhere in
the world and we just sent something
that holds real value potentially all
across the world in about 30 seconds
isn't that crazy
of course we can go back to account one
and then we can open up our contract
interactions
right here you can click it go to
transaction data and then
go to send right here
open activity log and then click
transaction confirmed this is going to
open up the ropes robeston test network
and as you can see we have our
transaction hash the status block
confirmations and the value of ethereum
send we can also see from which account
to which account was this sent so let's
go to our account one and you can notice
that now we have a few interactions here
the first one was the contract creation
and we have two outs one for sending and
one for storing you can also see the
current balance right here once again i
hope you're sharing my enthusiasm about
this because this is definitely a
revolutionary technology with that said
we can now focus on finishing up the
rest of jsx part which is the services
transactions and the footer once we have
those parts then we'll be able to
retrieve all of the store transactions
and then show them just below so now
we're going to move just a bit away from
all that blockchain functionality and
focus on writing pure jsx using react
and tailwind but we're gonna be back to
blockchain in no time
let's start with the services section
let's go to file explorer and then
services
inside of here we're gonna import a few
icons
the first one is bs
shield
fill
check and this is coming from react dash
icons forward slash bs
the second icon on our list is import bi
search
alt
and this is coming from
react dash icons forward slash bi
and the last icon on our list is import
ri
heart to fill
and that's from react icons forward
slash ri
now for our services let's simply create
a div
and this div is going to have a class
name
equal to flex
with dash full
justify dash center items dash center
and gradient
dash bg dash services
now we can save that and we can put our
browser and editor side by side so that
we can see the changes we make there we
go
now inside of this div we're going to
create one more div
and that div is going to have a class
name equal to
flex
mf
flex dash row
flex dash column
item stash center
justify dash between
mdp-20
as in padding 20
and padding y meaning on top and bottom
is going to be 12
and padding on x axis is going to be
four as soon as we save that you're
going to notice that we have a bit more
padding right here
now let's create one final div inside of
which the content will go so right here
we can say class name is equal to flex
dash one
flicks
flex dash call
justify dash start and then items dash
start
inside of there we can finally create an
h1 element right here
and let's say something like services
that we
and then inside of a new row we can say
something like br
as in break tag to provide some space
and then say continue
to improve
like this
if we save that we're gonna notice that
it's right here but it is dark so let's
provide some class names class name is
equal to
text white
there we go
now let's also make it larger by saying
text 3 xl
on small devices we can make it even
larger by saying text 5 xl there we go
and finally let's give it padding y 2
and text gradient
there we go services that we continue to
improve now just below this div we're
going to have one more div
and this is going to be for our services
cards so right here let's give it a
class name
that's going to be flex dash one
flex
flex dash call
justify dash start and items dash center
there we go now we have this on the left
side
and right here we're gonna have our
services cards since we're gonna reuse
our service card three times and it's
going to be the same every time but the
only things that are going to change is
going to be the title subtitle icon and
caller for that reason we can create a
new component that we're going to reuse
and we're going to call that component
const
service
card
and that's going to be equal to
like this to an arrow function component
with an instant return
each service card can have a div
with a class name equal to flex
flex dash row
justify dash start
items dash center
white dash glass
morphism
padding dash 3
margin dash 2
cursor dash pointer
and then on hover
shadow dash xl
great
now just so we can see the changes we're
making inside of our card let's make use
of that card just below right here we
can call our first service card
component right here
as a self-closing tag and now we can
provide some parameters
in this case we're going to provide a
caller so let's do bg dash
and then in square brackets that's going
to be hash
2 9 5
2 e 3.
great below that we're going to also
give it a title which is going to be
security
guaranteed
like this
let's also give it an icon by saying
icon and we're gonna provide a component
bs shield fill check
with a font size is equal to 21
and class name is equal to text dash
white and the last thing we can provide
is going to be a subtitle so we can say
subtitle is equal to
and we can put some placeholder text
something like security
is
guaranteed
we always maintain
privacy
and maintain the quality
of our products something like that
should be fine
and that's going to be it for our
service card
now we know that our service card
accepts a few properties it accepts a
color
title
icon and subtitle and all of these are
props so we need to destructure them
right at the top meaning we have to put
them inside of curly braces
so now inside of this div we can create
one more div
this one is going to be for the icon so
let's give it a class name
and then we're going to make it dynamic
like this
with dash 10
height dash 10
and that should be enough to already see
it so right inside of here we can
dynamically render the icon as soon as
we save that you notice that something
appeared here but we cannot yet see it
so let's continue by providing more
classes
rounded dash full
flex
justify dash center
items center
and then finally let's give it a color
like this if we save that you're gonna
notice a blue dot right here and that's
not exactly how it should look like just
to show you how a finished version
should look like i pulled up the
finished site and you can see right here
we need to have an icon a white icon on
all of these circle backgrounds so let's
go back to our app and figure out why
cannot we see our icon yet and i've just
noticed the reason in here i had icons
instead of just icon if we fix that the
icon is going to appear right here
and now below this icon div we can have
one more div
this div is going to have a class name
equal to margin left 5 flex flex dash
call flex dash 1
and inside of there we can have an h3
that's going to simply render out the
title like this
and below that we can have a paragraph
that's going to simply render the
subtitle of course the entire text is
dark right now so let's fix it
let's give it a class
name
equal to
mt as in margin top dash 2
text dash white
text lg
and that's going to be it for our h1
for our padding that's going to be text
wide text small sm
and also on medium devices we can say
width is going to be 9 divided by 12 or
9 out of 12.
great so now we have this great card
and you still might be wondering why did
we create this separate component if
we're just going to render it right here
well the reason is now that we extracted
the code we can reuse it as many times
as possible and that is the beauty of
react so now if i duplicate this two
times
and if i change the bg color a bit the
second one is going to be 8 9 8 4 5 f 8
like this
in here we can say something like
best
exchange
rates
the icon can be
bi
search alt
and then for the last one we can change
the color to be f
eight
four five five zero
in here we can say something like
fastest
transactions
and the icon is going to be ri
hard to fill
if we now save this you can immediately
notice that we get two more of these
cards instantly without any work needed
it just looks like we're missing the
caller for the second service card so
let's see this is going to be just eight
nine four like this and we immediately
get this nice purple color
now if you expand this a bit more
you'll see that this is looking great we
have our initial section and with that
we have our services
now that we have our services done let's
also check how our services look on
mobile devices so let's open device
toolbar
and go to mobile
and as you can see it looks like we're
missing just one thing and that is to
make this into a column on mobile
devices to fix this we can go back to
the code and right here say
flex dash column
there we go and then say on medium
devices md
flex dash row
so now for medium or higher we're gonna
have a row and on mobile devices we're
gonna have a column
so it's looking great on mobile and now
if we go back you're gonna notice that
this looks great on desktop as well
now that that is done let's focus on
rendering out the list of our
transactions to do that we can go back
to our file explorer and go to
transactions
just to immediately have some
transactions to work with we can go to
our utils and down in the description
you'll find the dummy data file in here
and you can just paste it in here
this is going to be a list of six demo
transactions just so we immediately have
some data that we can start rendering
out on the screen
so you can just paste it inside of the
utils once you find it down in the
description
with that said let's open up our
transactions and right here we can
import react
as well as use context
and that's coming from react
then we can import our transaction
contacts because we're going to
definitely use it later on once we want
to fetch real transactions so that's
coming from that dot slash context and
then transaction context and here i have
a typo that's going to be just react we
also want to fetch that dummy data so we
can say import dummy data from
dot slash utils and then forward slash
dummy data
inside of here we can render a div
and that div is going to have a class
name right here
equal to flex
with dash full
justify dash center
items center 2xl
px20 that's going to give it a padding
x20 on extra large devices
then we want to have the gradient
dash bg dash transactions
if we save that nothing is going to
happen yet but now we can add something
inside of this div
let's add a div that's going to have a
class name equal to
flex
flex dash call
mdp-12
py-12 and also px-4
that's going to provide it with some
padding and right here we want to have a
heading that says something like latest
transactions
if we have our account connected but if
we don't have our account connected in
that case we wanted to say something
like connect
your account
to see the latest transactions
so to do that we can pull some data
using the context
right here at the top we can say const
current account
and that's going to be equal to
use context and then we simply pass the
context we want to fetch and that is
transaction context
so what we can say
open a dynamic block and if there is a
current account
in that case we want to render
that's going to be an h3
it's going to have a class name
equal to
text white
text
3 xl
text center
and margin y dash 2.
inside of there we can simply say latest
transactions
and now if we don't have the account
connected
then we can create the else part of our
ternary
and copy that same h3
paste it here but now we're gonna change
it to say connect your account to see
the latest changes
great
now we can remove these comments because
we have our heading
let's take a look
right now i can see connect your account
to see the latest transactions that's
great
and i also have this button this might
be different for you because you might
be already connected
i paused the recording of the video for
some time so metamask logged me out this
is going to happen from time to time you
just have to retype your password and
you'll be straight back in
there we go
now i'm going to reload the page
and as you can see we can see latest
transactions that's great one thing that
we were also missing at the start was
the address right here we implemented
the entire transaction sending process
but we never got into the point where we
show the address of the connected
account on this card which is definitely
a nice detail
so let's go back to our welcome
right here
and remember our current account is
coming through the context
so now just below
we can find where are we listing the
address right here
and we can simply render the current
account
there we go
as you can see that is quite a long
string
so to shorten it we're going to create a
new utility function inside of utils
called
shorten
address
dot js inside of here we can say export
const
shorten
address
and that's going to be a function that
accepts the address
and then instantly returns a template
string
where we're going to take the address
slice it from the start and take only
the first 5 characters or this is going
to be 6 because it's starting from 0.
then we want to say dot dot we can copy
this same part again
and instead of slicing from 0 to 5 we
want to slice from address
dot length
minus 4
all the way to the end so we're taking
the first five characters and then also
showing the last four now we can go back
to welcome
and right here we can import
our shorten
address function which is coming from
that slash utils forward slash shortened
address
and the only thing we have to do
is right here where we're rendering the
current account
we can simply call the shortened address
and paste the current account into it
that's going to give us this nice format
and that's the exact same thing that
metamask does right here
great and the only reason we put it in
utils is because we're going to use it
in transactions as well so right here we
can also immediately import
shorten
address
from dot slash utils forward slash
shorten address
great now that we have this heading
right here we of course have to loop
through the transactions
we can do that by providing a div right
here
let's fix this
that div is going to have a class name
equal to flex
flex-wrap
justify dash center
items center and mt-10
there we go and now inside of there we
can create a new dynamic block
we can render our dummy transactions for
now so we can simply say
dummy
data
and then we can call a dot reverse
method on it to reverse it because we
want to start from the last to the first
or rather from the newest to the last
and then finally we can also map over it
by saying transaction
get the index
and then instantly return something and
that something is going to be a new
component that we're going to create
which is called transaction card like
this as a self-closing component we can
give it a key equal to i
and also right here we can spread all of
the properties that we get from
transaction that's going to take all the
properties from here and put it right
into our transaction card as props
and these things are going to be id url
message timestamp address from amount
and address 2.
so inside of our transaction card we'll
be able to work with all of these values
let's create our transaction card right
here
const transaction
card
is equal to
a functional component
and as we said we're going to get all of
these values
address 2
address from
timestamp
message
keyword
amount
and url
and that has to be in curly braces
because it has to be structured for now
let's simply return
a string that's going to say transaction
there we go
and we should be able to see there we go
six time transaction transaction
transaction transaction
but now let's implement the jsx for each
one of these transaction cards
let's do that right here instead of this
return
so let's return a div instead of a
string
and that div is going to have a class
name equal to
bg dash
square bracket
and then hash
one eight one
nine one eight
also margin-4 so m-4 flex and then
flex-1
inside of here we'll have to provide
different widths for different device
sizes
and we can do that in a new line still
inside of this class name string first
on two xl devices we can set the min
dash
width or just w and then in square
brackets 450 pixels now we can duplicate
that line and then set the max dash
width equal to 500 pixels on two xl
devices
now we can copy that
paste it below
and then on small devices so sm we want
to set the minimum to be
270 pixels
and then let's do 300 for the maximum on
small devices
we can also provide the flex dash call
rounded dash md and finally hover
shadow dash 2 xl
great now inside of there we can have a
div that's going to contain our content
so there's div let's give it a class
name equal to flex
flex dash call
items center
w dash full and empty three there we go
now we have these gray rectangles
now we can render out all of the data
for our specific transaction
so let's do a div we can give it a class
name equal to display dash flex
justify
dash
start
with dash full
mb as in margin bottom dash 6 and
padding dash 2.
now inside of that div we can render two
different anchor tags so let's create an
anchor tag right here
there we go
and this display flex was supposed to be
just flex
so right here we can create an anchor
tag that's going to have an href equal
to and now bear with me
https colin forward slash forward slash
robston
dot ether
scan
dot io forward slash address forward
slash and then dollar sign curly braces
address from like this
of course we have to make it a dynamic
template string like this
and also at the end
close it right here let's put this into
a new line
this anchor tag is also going to have a
target underscore blank
and it's also going to have a url equal
to no opener no referrer it is advisable
to put this tag right here whenever
you're using the target underscore blank
inside of that anchor tag we can create
a paragraph that's going to have a class
name equal to text white text dash base
let's fix this right here as well
and it's going to say
from
and right here we can call the shorten
address function and provide the address
from into it
that way we'll now have the address from
for every single transaction and when
you click it you'll be able to see that
address and all of the transactions on
the robston test network on etherscan
this is just providing that extra level
of connectedness to the blockchain
now let's also duplicate this anchor tag
and just below we can right here put the
address
this is also going to be address 2 and
we can say
2. now we have the from and also to
below that anchor tag we can create a
paragraph
that's going to have a class name equal
to text dash white
text dash base
and right here we can render the amount
is equal to amount of ethereum
there we go
it looks like we don't need this to be a
flex container at all we simply need to
have a full width
so you can simply remove the flex and
justify start from here
there we go and now we have the from the
two which are clickable and also the
amount of ethereum being sent
finally if there is a message
with that specific transaction so
message
and end
in that case we can render a new react
fragment it's going to have a break tag
right here to divide it a bit
and it's going to have a paragraph
that's going to have a class
name
equal to text white
text dash base
and we can simply say message is equal
to
message
there we go
since these are our demo transactions
they don't have a message but all of the
ones sent through our own network will
have a message property
great and before actually rendering out
the image which is going to go right
here we can render the timestamp the
timestamp is going to be a div that's
going to have a class name equal to
bg-black
p x 5
w dash max
rounded dash 3 x l
minus
dash
mt-5 and shadow dash 2 xl
right now that's not really noticeable
but we have a small rectangle right here
and we can provide a paragraph right
inside of that div right here
that p tag is going to have a class
name
equal to text dash
and then in square brackets hash
37c
7da
and it's going to have
dash bold
in there we can simply render the
timestamp
right now we got an error because at the
top i misspelled the timestamp
so if we spell it correctly you can see
it right here
of course this is not yet aligning
properly because we don't yet have a gif
corresponding to our keyword that we're
mentioning right here
and we can also fix this keyword right
here i noticed that i misspelled it
so let's search for keyword and let's
remove this o which is a dipole right
here
that's a lot better
to fetch our gifts we're going to use
developers.gifi.com
the world's most popular gif platform
so let's create a new account right here
you can go to sign up you'll have to
enter your details and then i'll see you
right in their dashboard
and there we go if you successfully
created your account you should be on
your own account page
so now let's explore the giffy platform
by going to giphy
and we're not interested in these gifs
right here we want to go to
developers.gifi.com
now you can click read the docs right
here or create the account whatever it
says
and then at the bottom left if you're
successfully logged in you can click
create an app
in this case we're going to choose a
giphy api because we don't need any gif
creation tools we simply need to be able
to query all the existing gifs
and click next step
we can enter our app's name which is
going to be crypt in my case and how
will we use our gift key that's going to
be to query
different
gifs
and let's click right here and create an
app there we go you just got your api
key and that's all that we need we can
copy it
go back to our application
and we're going to create a new dot env
file
so right inside of our client folder not
inside of the source
right here right click and click new
file and call it dot env
instead of react underscore app in this
case we're going to use vite underscore
giphy underscore api is equal to and
then you can paste your api key right
inside of here
now you can open up the terminal press
ctrl c to stop it and then just npm run
dev again to run it and then you'll have
access to your giphy api environment
variable
now we were on our transactions page
right here where we had everything
besides our gif image
so what do we have to do to fetch this
image
well we're going to create a custom hook
so right here we can create a new folder
in the source folder called hooks
and right inside of there we can create
a new use
fetch
dot jsx hook
inside of here we'll write the logic for
fetching the gif based on a specific
keyword
but since this is not related to the
application
to fetch the gif we can import use
effect
and use state and that's coming from
react
we can also say const api underscore key
is equal to import
dot meta dot env dot
vite underscore giphy underscore api
this is going to give us access to that
api key variable
then we can create a new use fetch hook
a custom hook to be more precise
right here we can create a new use state
field which is going to be the gif url
and at the start it's going to be set to
an empty string
then we can create a cons
fetch
gifs function
that's going to be an async function
and it's going to have a try and catch
block
inside of here we can try getting the
response from the gephi api by saying
await
fetch
and then in here we have to enter the
api we want to fetch from
and to find that api we can go into
documentation right here
and we want to fetch specific apis so
let's go to quick start guide and let's
try to find different endpoints
so right here gif and sticker endpoints
search endpoint and you can see that it
is
api.giphy.com v1 gifs and then search
this is exactly what we need
so let's copy this
paste it into this string right here but
we have to provide
https column forward slash forward slash
at the start and then we have to provide
some parameters things like queue as in
query and api key
so at the end let's simply say question
mark to provide parameters
api underscore key is equal to
and then dollar sign curly braces
we have to turn this into a template
string to be able to use logic inside of
our string right here we can render our
api underscore key
and then we're going to say end
q is equal to
that's going to be dollar sign curly
braces
keyword
dot split and we want to split it by
space
because someone might actually type a
few words into our input field right
here
and how are we going to search for gifs
then
so we're going to first split our string
with spaces like this and then we're
going to join it right back by saying
join and then we don't pass a space
right here that way we'll just have one
word without spaces in our keyboard at
all times
and finally at the end we can say and
limit is equal to one because we need to
be able to find just one gif
now that we have our query we can
destructure the data from the response
by saying const in curly braces data is
equal to a weight response dot json and
finally we want to set the state of our
gif so set gif url is going to be equal
to
data 0
question mark dot images question mark
dot down size underscore medium dot url
and let's also put a question mark dot
right here
and to handle the catch we can go to our
utils dummy data we can copy one demo
url from these
go back and simply say set gif url to be
equal to a string of that specific gif
that's going to be a random gif so if a
new gif isn't found we can just use a
demo one
and finally when are we calling this
fetch gif function
well we'll call it just below inside of
the use effect
our use effect is going to happen
whenever the keyword changes so right
here we're going to pass the keyword
and the keyword is going to be coming
through props to our use fetch function
or use fetch custom hook
so right here we can say keyword and
whenever the keyword changes we can
simply say if there is a keyword in that
case we want to call
fetch
gifs function
and the last and only thing that our use
fetch function is going to do is it's
going to return
a gif
url
and finally we have to export default
use
fetch
again just make sure that this specific
query for fetching gifs is written
correctly and also that you don't have
any mistakes in the logic right here
if something doesn't seem to be working
in that case you can check the github
repository and find the use fetch.jsx
file and compare it with your own
so now that we have our use fetch
function we can go back
we can import that's going to be use
fetch from dot slash hooks
forward slash use fetch and now right
inside of here inside of our transaction
card we can say const gif url is equal
to
use fetch and we're gonna pass in an
object that's going to contain the
keyboard
great so where are we going to render
that image that's going to be right here
we can simply say
image as a self-closing tag
and then we're going to provide a source
which is going to be just a gif url
or url this is going to be for our demo
images
we can give it an alt which is going to
say give
and then finally we can give it a class
name
w dash full
h-64
2xl
then we're going to make it height 96
rounded dash medium
shadow dash lg
and object dash cover
now if we save that
you can see right here something seems
to be broken it always has to be broken
first only so that it can work later so
let's see what are we missing
i'm going to open up our console reload
the page
and right now we shouldn't even be
fetching real gifs because we're
rendering just the dummy data so in here
we should have or and not just one
single straight line
as soon as we add or our gifs are right
here there we go
so now we have the six of our dummy
transactions
and looks like the timestamp is going
into the image which shouldn't really be
the case
so let's see
the image and this div with a timestamp
should be outside with the entirety of
the other content
if we save that
now you'll see that the timestamp goes
nicely over the image
this is looking great but of course
these are just dummy transactions these
are not the real transactions that we
send through our network and they're not
read from the blockchain anybody could
have done this right this is not a web
3.0 application
so right now let's just finish up our
site with the footer which is going to
be incredibly quick and then we're going
to replace these transactions to show
the real transactions that are sent
through our ethereum blockchain
to implement the code for our footer we
can go of course to our footer component
and right here the only thing we're
going to import is going to be the logo
right here
and that's coming from dot slash dot
slash images forward slash and then
that's going to be logo dot png
everything else we're going to code
straight away
so right inside of here we can create a
div
and this div is going to have a class
name
right here which is going to be equal to
with dash full
flex
md justify dash center
justify dash between
items dash center
flex dash call
padding dash 4
gradient bg dash footer
there we go now we have our entire page
fill in these gradients
inside of that div we're gonna have one
more div
and this div is going to have a class
name
equal to
with dash full
flex
on small devices flex dash row and
usually flex dash column
justify dash between
items dash center and margin y dash 4.
finally we're going to create a div
that's going to contain our image so
right here we can create an image
that image is going to have the source
equal to logo
alt is going to be logo and class name
is going to be width dash 32 if we save
that you can see the crypt logo right
here
let's provide some class names to the
outer div some things like flex
flex dash and then 0.5 this is going to
take just half of the space
then justify dash center and items dash
center there we go now we positioned it
right here
and below that we want to have one more
div this div is going to have a class
name equal to flex
flex-1
justify dash evenly
items center
flex-wrap
on small devices
mt-0
usually empty-5
and with dash full
now inside of there we can put our links
and these links are just going to be
different paragraphs
let's do something like market and then
let's give it a class name
equal to text white
text dash base
text dash center
mx-2
and cursor dash pointer
there we go and now we're going to
duplicate this four times or rather
three more times and change this to say
exchange
then something like tutorials
and finally wallets
and there we go we have our four links
with this script logo right here
we can also do something more for our
footer so let's create one more div
but make sure to do it below these two
divs
and right here we can give this div a
class name equal to flex
justify dash center
items dash center
flex dash call
mt-5 inside of there we can create a
paragraph that paragraph is going to
have a class name equal to text dash
white
text dash small and text center inside
of there we can say come join us
and then just below that we can enter
our email
something like info at cryptomastery.com
and there we go come join us is right
inside of here and that is one great
thing about custom emails and custom
domain names if you purchase the
hostinger's shared hosting plan you're
going to get plenty of email addresses
completely for free and then you can
create your addresses such as info ad
and then
yourdomain.com
if you're building a serious site or a
portfolio website it definitely makes
sense to have this as it provides an
extra level of authenticity to your site
someone is much more likely to purchase
something or use your site if you have a
custom domain like cryptomastery.com
so if you haven't yet purchased the
hostinger plan you can still do that by
the end of this video
now let's continue and finish up our
footer by creating a self-closing div
tag with a class name equal to sm colon
w dash and then in square brackets 90
percent like this
with dash full
height dash in square brackets
0.25 pixels
and then vg dash gray dash 400
mt-5
this is going to create this nice line
right here and finally we have to have
the last div of our footer
so let's create that div
this div is also going to have a class
name
and it's also going to start with small
width 90 so we can copy that
with dash full
flex
justify dash between
items center
and mt-3
now inside of there we can copy this
paragraph where we say com join us
paste it here
and we're gonna say add cryptomastery
2022 and we can duplicate that one more
time and we're going to use that famous
line all rights reserved
there we go this is looking so much
better
this just concluded the entire design of
our website starting from the nice
welcome page with the form to send
ethereum across blockchain nice header
at the top the services page latest
transactions page and finally the footer
now is the time that we get back to some
blockchain work and actually retrieve
the list of all transactions that were
sent across our network
let's do that right away
to get our transactions we're going to
go into context and then transaction
context
now we can go just below our check if
wallet is connected function and right
here we can create one new function
which is called const
check if
transactions
exist
and that's going to be another async
function like this
it's going to have a try and catch block
and in here we also want to get that
ethereum contract so we can copy that
line from here khan's transaction
contract is equal to get ethereum
contract
paste it here
and then we want to get the transaction
count which we are already doing here so
we can copy that from here
that happens once we are sending the
transaction so we get the transaction
contract and then we get the number of
transactions
the only thing that this function is
going to do is going to be window dot
local storage
dot set item and in here we want to set
the transaction count to be equal to
transaction count that's going to be it
and we can copy the error from here
because it's going to be the same
now we can call this function just below
calling our check if wallet is connected
right here and that's going to be it
that's essentially just going to set up
the current number of transactions so
that for every new transaction we know
which one is it
and now finally the part you've been all
waiting for we can create a new function
just below our handle change which is on
top
called
const
get all transactions
that's another async function that's
going to have a try and catch block
inside of it we also have to check if
people have metamask installed so we can
say if no ethereum object then return
please install metamask and the only
thing we have to do is say const
available transactions is a weight
transaction contract and then
dot
get all transactions this is a special
function we created on our smart
contract that's going to return all the
transactions
but we first have to get this
transaction contract and to do that we
can simply copy this line construction
contract is equal to get ethereum
contract
let's paste it here
and that's going to be it now we can
console.log all available transactions
right here
and also for the error let's simply
console.log that error
there we go
we can reload the page
and we have to call get all transactions
somewhere
but of course we won't be able to see
this console log because this function
is never called
so in the check if wallet is connected
right here we want to get all available
transactions
great now we can reload the page go to
console
in the info right here we can see an
array with one element if i'm not
mistaken we only made one test
transaction and this is it you can see
it has keys from 0 to 5 and also it has
some object properties such as the
amount keyword message receiver sender
and timestamp
but this is in a bit of a weird format
here with the numbers as keys and then
the real keys so let's create a new
structured transaction we can do that by
saying const structured transactions is
going to be equal to available
transactions
dot map and then we're gonna get each
transaction
and we simply want to instantly return
an object you do that by putting
parentheses and then inside of them an
object sign so
what do we want to do we want to have
the address
to property which is going to be equal
to transaction
dot receiver then we want to have the
address from property which is going to
be equal to transaction dot sender
then we want to have a timestamp which
is going to be equal to new date
transaction dot timestamp
and then dot 2 number
times 1000
and finally dot to
locale
string
this is going to give us that nice time
and date representation the thing i'm
referring to is this format right here
then we're gonna have a comma
then we need a message which is simply
going to be transaction
dot message
we need to have a keyword which is going
to be transaction
dot keyword
and finally the amount is going to be
parse int
transaction
dot amount dot underscore hex
and then we're going to multiply that by
10 to the power of 18
because if you think about it we already
discussed it that all values are written
in hexadecimal and not only hexadecimal
ethereum but hexadecimal wei which is
the subunit of ethereum so to get
ethereum we have to multiply it by
extremely large 10 to the power of 18.
that is going to give us the real
ethereum amount now that we have r i
have a typo here structured transactions
we can simply set them to the state by
saying
set transactions and that's going to be
structured transactions
great and let's also console log them so
we can see if everything is right if we
go back
reload the page
we should be able to see that one
transaction set transactions is not
defined let's see
that's because we don't yet have the use
state hook for our transactions so we
can create transactions and set
transactions and at the start that's
going to be set to an empty array if we
save that and reload the page you can
now see that we have an array with one
object and that is a nicely formatted
transaction but we have few issues one
is with the amount and the other one is
with the timestamp the amount seems too
big and the timestamp is an invalid date
so let's fix those right away for our
timestamp we need to say newdate
transaction.timestamp.2 number but this
here is supposed to be a function
so if we now save this
and reload the page now
our timestamp is going to be correct it
is right here and for the amount we have
to say parseint
transaction.amount dot underscore hex
and then this here is not going to be
times is going to be divided by 10 to
the power of 18. if we now save this
reload
you can see that the amount is 0.0005
ethereum
great so now we have the list of our
transactions
and we can go back to our transactions
page
and instead of rendering dummy data
we no longer need that
we can simply render real transactions
right here that we're going to get from
the context so transactions
we render those transactions right here
but don't forget we have to pass them
right here
into the context
so value
we're going to pass the transactions as
well as the is loading state because we
have to use that as well
now we can reload the page before
sending another test transaction let's
go to our welcome page and i remembered
that we forgot to implement the loading
because if you remember right now we
have this to false to never show a
loader
but at the top we can simply get the is
loading from context right now because
we're passing it through the context
so if we scroll down now we can simply
say if is loading render out the loader
else render out a send now button so now
if we scroll down we should be able to
see our test transaction
and there it is
from our own account and we can verify
that if we go to meta mask
0x53c
and there we go it starts with 0x53c
ends with 73aa and that seems correct
and we indeed sent 0.005 ethereum and
the message was test and here is a gif
representing our keyword of test as well
great now to verify that everything
absolutely works let's send a few more
transactions
i'm going to again go to metamask
accounts account two
click this miss right here and copy the
address
i'm gonna paste it right here
let's send another 0.005
or let's be generous and send a bit more
0.001
the gif can in this case be hello
and the message can be
hello from account one and let's go
ahead and click send now
we get that metamask notification
i'm gonna click confirm
and we get that contract interaction and
i'm again going to press confirm
the loading now works and this is
looking phenomenal in about 10 to 30
seconds the transaction should go
through and we should be able to see it
just below
and there we go the loading stopped i'm
gonna reload the page
and now if we scroll down
as you can see we have two transactions
right here
this one is saying hello as we specified
and the message hello from account one
is here
0.001 ethereum so that's looking good as
well
so there we go that's it we have our two
transactions and just for good measure
let's try to send one more
i'm again going to paste the same
address of the account too
let's do something incredibly big this
time
let's see how much do we have in our
account
0.14
so let's do 0.1
the 10th of one ethereum and in this
case instead of hello let's try with hi
and the message can be
here's a gift for you
and let's click send
again we'll have to verify it through
our meta mask
confirm and then contract interaction
confirm as well we have that nice
loading and as soon as it's done we can
reload the page
or we can also go to our transaction
context
right here and we also increment the
transaction number we can do
window.reload
that's going to reload the page as soon
as the transaction is done
and there we go hi there here's a gift
for you and let's check if our ethereum
wallet 2 actually received the ethereum
and there it is 0.1015
that is it
as i've said the other account could
have been on the other part of the world
and in just about 20 to 30 seconds you
can send any amount of money through the
blockchain network isn't that crazy
with that said we're slowly coming to
the end of this video this has been a
phenomenal project and i haven't been
this excited for a video in quite some
time now and for the end i'm going to
teach you how to deploy this project to
hostinger that way we're going to have a
custom domain and you can also create as
many custom emails as you want with that
said let's go ahead and deploy this
project together right away
and we are back on our hostingers
dashboard i already purchased the domain
cryptomastery.com
if you purchased yours it's going to be
right here as well if you haven't you
can do that right away again the link is
down in the description
if you haven't yet connected the domain
to your setup the setup is going to be
right here but if you already connected
it it's going to be right here under
premium shared hosting and then your
domain name right here
in this case we're going to go to manage
you can scroll all the way down and go
to the file manager
you can click this new file manager
right here
that's going to lead you to your age
panel you can go into the public
underscore html document and right now
we just have this default.php
which you can delete right here
and press yes now we have to put our
build folder right into here and we can
create our build folder by going back to
our application
we can close all of our files by holding
ctrl and then pressing w
collapse our file tree
and then open up the terminal by going
to view and then terminal
we can stop it from running by pressing
ctrl c and then y
we can clear it and while still staying
in the client we can run npm run build
this is going to create an optimized
version ready for production and there
we go with the white it's incredibly
quick
we have our deployed version under dist
so you can right click it and then click
reveal in file explorer
once you've done that you can simply
drag and drop only the dist folder right
into here
once you open this in file explorer it
should look something like this and then
you can enter this folder
the only thing you have to do is drag
and drop the assets and the index.html
right into here that's going to take
just a moment and your files are going
to be right here right away
and that's about it if we now go back to
our hosting panel scroll to the top and
click your domain name right here you
should be able to see that it's going to
load out instantly
but there's one really important thing
left to do and that is to enable the ssl
certificate because our site is
currently not secure
so we can go back
we can search for ssl right here
click it
and then hostinger just makes it so easy
the only thing we have to do is say
install ssl
ssl is being installed as we speak and
this process usually takes just about a
minute
i was wrong it actually took just about
five seconds i reload the page and there
it was
so now if we go back in here and if you
reload the page
as you can notice we have this lock
right here which means that connection
is secure
and again especially with cryptocurrency
applications having a custom domain name
ssl certificate
fast load times and a custom email
definitely comes in handy because there
are a lot of cryptocurrency related
scams and you need your page to be
secure and reliable with that said let's
see if our blockchain transactions are
going to work on our deployed site as
well
as you can see we haven't yet connected
our metamask wallet to our deployed site
and that's why we have just these three
dots right here so let's click connect
wallet
a notification is going to appear
and in this case let's connect the
account number two
next
and connect
just like that our address appeared
right here we can open our meta mask
go to account number one
dismiss copy the account address
paste it here
let's send 0.1 back
let's do something like blockchain
and say
here take your
ethereum back
and a smiley face and let's press send
now sending ethereum
confirm
and then contract interaction confirm as
well
the loading is happening let's go to
account 1 and wait for the transaction
to happen and there we go in about 30
seconds the transaction went through and
we now have 0.14 ethereum on our account
1 on robsten test network
let's reload the page
scroll down
and there we go
our blockchain gif stored on the
blockchain forever
looks like ethereum is climbing to fight
the bitcoin king
and all of this is happening on our new
deployed domain which means that
absolutely everyone can create their own
metamask account wallet and send
ethereum through the application that
you created and deployed phenomenal job
thank you so much for watching this
video it's been a crazy experience at
least for me connecting a react
application to the blockchain it's a
revolutionary technology and it's going
to definitely take the world by storm in
the upcoming months or years
so if you'd like to see more web 3.0
videos just let me know in the comments
like this video and share it
with that said thank you so much for
watching and have a wonderful day
[Music]
you